Kev, Kev.
>> Tim, Tim.
>> Good to see you, man.
>> Good to see you, and let's figure out
which one they're going to share.
>> Cheers. All right. Well,
you know, I know the cool kids are down
on alcohol, but every once in a while, I
think there's a place for it.
>> There's a time and place.
>> And this is the time.
>> I think this [laughter] is the time and
the place, and I think paying a tax for
it the next day is a feature and not a
bug.
>> Are you getting taxed harder
>> Oh, of course, yeah.
>> getting worse?
>> Every old bastard
>> Yeah, I know.
>> That's gender neutral, gets taxed as you
can process ethanol
less and less well over time. But, I'm
cool with it. I I don't have that much,
but today has been hectic.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, take a little
take take a little edge off.
And people may not like the sound of
that. It's a little antiquated, maybe,
for all the cool ketamine kids, no
offense.
>> [laughter]
>> But,
>> Don't put that [\h__\h] on me.
I tried one time, and I get freaking
[laughter]
the bastard
>> go once, and then they call me the god
[\h__\h]
>> [laughter]
>> You can't get around it.
I still stand by that experience.
When you're doing it in a supervised
setting by a medical professional
>> go.
>> No, I've been telling you, it's you've
done it.
>> Of course, [snorts] I have.
>> Okay, so there we go.
>> Well, yeah, because I wanted to be able
to speak.
>> you at a party one time, and you were
just like
>> That's not true. That's [laughter] not
true.
Still have all my nostrils intact. No
ketamine cramps, you know.
>> I don't even know what that is. Is that
a thing?
>> That's when you use too much.
>> Okay.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Tell me about
>> Oh, yeah, I heard something bad on the
bladder.
>> Yeah, your bladder can get a little
grumpy, or a lot grumpy,
>> Yeah.
>> as the case might be.
>> Yeah, I'm good.
>> You know, I'm good.
>> Kevin,
random show number 3,479.
>> Yeah, you know what's crazy, dude, is I
looked up a random show the other day,
and you had a bit of hair. Like
>> [laughter]
>> like way way back in the day.
>> yeah.
>> We We babies.
>> I know.
>> So much [\h__\h] has happened.
>> The only constant I think is like maybe
like Toaster, who's barely alive. Like
>> [laughter]
>> you know.
>> Toaster, I know. Seriously.
Toaster was a tiny, tiny little pup.
>> Yeah.
>> Who was chewing through the XLR cables.
>> Oh my god.
>> Your couch in San Francisco way, way,
way back in the day.
>> Toaster's 15. And I'll tell a quick
little story. A week ago
I get this call
and Derek calls me and she's like you
got to get over the house. Toaster is
shaking violently. And he's 15. He's
like running into walls and [\h__\h] You
know, he's getting up there. And his
legs are collapsing so he can't stand
up. And he couldn't stand up. And he's
shaking violently. And I'm like
just flying over there.
>> Mhm.
>> I throw him in my car. He's on my lap.
Driving, you know, to get to this
emergency vet as fast as possible.
And he just sprays [\h__\h] all over me.
Like literally I I heard it like I I
felt his stomach be like
>> Oh, here we go.
>> 10 seconds later I'm not even talking
like oh like oh he had a little [\h__\h]
Like no, no, no, no. Like shotgun
against the car door. Like the whole
thing. And it's all down my pants.
>> Poor Toaster.
>> I know, but you know what's funny, dude?
It's like I rushed him in and long story
short he's okay now.
>> What was it?
>> He had gone into the vet the day prior
and he was so nervous that he stood for
he had to be there for like a multi-hour
blood draw
>> Mhm.
>> cuz he where he had some other issues
and he stood for like 6 hours straight.
>> That's too long for an old dog.
>> can only stand for like 10 minutes. Like
max. And so he had just overtaxed
himself and got like there's a syndrome
that they can get when they're like
super stressed out and all that.
>> Sure. So, little Molly's at it or big
Molly. She's on the floor right here.
>> She's sleeping.
>> Molly's 12.
>> That's crazy. But long story short he's
okay. But I thought to myself it's so
weird cuz I mean I walked in there and
there was like [\h__\h] and like I'm
literally I'm in tears cuz I think I'm
about to have to put down my dog.
>> Yeah, of course.
>> And I just thought it's okay. I'll do
this any day for this dude. When you
care about your animals that much, none
of that matters. Like you would do
anything for them. And it's just like
just that love. It's so crazy how much
you love these little beasts. Like it's
insane, dude. It's like a kid. It's like
a kid.
It's
>> wild to think about if you really sit
down and think about it. Some of these
super common daily
experiences like
communing with a dog or pointing and
having a dog recognize that you're
pointing for instance.
>> Mhm.
>> That's really rare in the animal
kingdom. That recognition of pointing as
just one example, but how unusual it is
that we have this And yes, we have cats.
I grew up with four cats and two dogs. I
get it. But in particular dogs as like
companions
co-hunters, etc. The fact that we have
evolved co-evolved in a sense
>> Mhm.
>> and sort of co-domesticated
also, right? It's not necessarily one
way. Read The Botany of Desire by
Michael Pollan for more on that.
is incredible.
>> Yeah.
>> Right? The fact that we have like we're
totally calm having this 60-plus pound
beast with giant fangs on the floor is
>> nuts.
>> Yeah, I mean I'm sure you've seen that
those Instagram posts where it's like
where I was and where I am now today.
And like they show like the wild like
wolf like out in the countryside like
eating a rabbit. And then they show like
a poodle in a tutu outfit and [\h__\h] like
all like dyed up and [\h__\h]
>> The meme is I'm going to go grab some
scraps from those weird monkeys. What's
the worst that could happen? And then
it's like 10,000 years later,
you're Chihuahua with a bonnet on.
>> What else going on, Kevin? I got a
couple things on my list. There's a lot
to talk about. There's a lot to talk
about. First I'll say that lately life
has been life-ing me. It's been doing
all the things. We lost a a dear
colleague Om Malik.
>> Oh, man. Very very sad.
>> very notorious like just amazing
early tech
>> just creative author writer
>> thinker
>> very sweet guy.
>> The nicest. The nicest.
>> And we lost him within the last week.
>> Yeah. Yeah, he passed away. So, that was
tough. That was
really tough. I found out when I was at
a a retreat. I went to a 5-day silent
meditation retreat, which is great. But,
bummer to hear that. But, I mean this is
the thing that I realized the other day.
I was
thinking about
you know, Toaster and Om and other stuff
I have going on and my mom getting older
and falling and all these things. And in
some sense it's unavoidable, number one.
And number two
I kind of wouldn't have it any other
way. It's what makes life interesting.
Like, when Om passed
>> You mean death?
>> Well, just the everything. The chaos of
it all.
>> Yeah.
>> If you can just take a step back and be
like, well or I could just be sitting
there living a really boring life and
nothing could be happening. Like, when
Om passed
what I felt was a severe sense of loss
and sorrow and sadness. But, I realized
that that gap is just love at the end of
the day. Because I wouldn't have it
unless I loved this man so much. Like, I
I cared for this person so much. How
lucky am I to have crossed paths with
this person?
>> Yeah, and you were
and you were tied in through True
Ventures, obviously, and prior to that.
>> Yeah. But, like anyone in general that
you lose that you love, you know? I
mean, when I lost my dad, like that is
just a gaping hole of love manifested
through sorrow and sadness.
>> Yeah.
>> And once you realize that, it's like,
wow, I had this great father that did
all these amazing things with me. And
you can kind of convert that or just be
okay with it. Not that you need to
change that feeling.
>> Recognize that it's a consequence of the
love you had.
>> consequence of the love, the deep love.
>> Yeah, you know, I heard about his
passing and I want to give credit where
credit is due for a few things. Matt
Mullenweg, our mutual friend, he was
incredibly close to him.
And I'm really grateful to Matt for a
few things. One, I mean many things. I
could give a long list, but there are a
few. One is he organized a trip to
Antarctica. I've never been to
Antarctica or hadn't and on that trip
were just a handful of people including
Om. So, I got to spend
>> quality time and trust me, when you're
>> [laughter]
>> in Antarctica, you are indoors most of
the time. What that means is you're
either trying to sleep in your tent, but
it's going to be during the summer, so
it's like a spotlight in your face 24
hours a day
or you're in one of these other
structures where you're probably like
having wine and junk food. Let's be
honest.
And [snorts] there's a lot of talking.
So, we got to hang out and Om was also
an avid photographer and so we got to
like go to this nearby emperor penguin
colony which was a once-in-a-lifetime
experience.
And [snorts]
you just sit and talk. And
if there were going to be any small
talk, which there wasn't going to be
with Om or me really for that matter, it
all falls away after the first half a
day. And then everybody's kind of like
psychologically naked, right? So, I
really want to thank Matt for that
opportunity to bond with Om. And I'd
spend a lot of time with him, but it was
always in these little bits and pieces.
You know, not for several days straight
where you're basically like locked in
together.
>> Yeah.
>> And separately, Matt introduced me to
this short blog post by someone who
typically writes very long blog posts,
Tim Urban, called The Tail End. I don't
know if I ever sent this to you.
>> Yeah, people should know by Wait But
Why. Wait But Why, fantastic blog.
>> And The Tail End makes the point among
many others that by the time you, I
think it's graduate from high school.
Let's assume you're headed off to
college
away from your parents. You've spent
something like 90, 95%
of the total hours you will ever spend
with your parents by the time you
graduate from high school.
>> Mhm.
>> And when you start to visualize that,
and Tim Urban's really good at laying it
out visually,
it can provoke some really profound
changes for me. I mean, just reading
that short blog post sent to me by Matt
ended up leading to taking my family on
these family trips as like awkward and
uncomfortable that was at points cuz my
family doesn't really
emote much.
>> Mhm.
>> And to stick us together in the way that
I was together with all of them, and
it's it can be super uncomfortable.
But making the effort, right? At least
feeling like, look,
this runway is not infinite.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's like, let me just make the
effort. And I'm glad I did because we
got to a point where it's like with my
dad's mobility is really compromised, he
needs a wheelchair now for a lot.
>> I just saw him a few days ago, and it
was great to see him, dude.
>> Yeah.
>> It was so great to see him.
>> He's so kind.
>> Yeah.
>> He's like, "Kevin!" Like, so happy. And
you know, he has his little cane, and it
was just like so sweet to see him, man.
>> I hadn't seen him for like years.
>> Long time.
>> It'd been like 7 years or something like
that.
>> like that.
>> And
I'm glad I took those trips because
before you know it, you can't do it
anymore. And it makes me think of you
mentioned meditation, this really good
short, I'll call it a meditation for
simplicity, but
>> [snorts]
>> it's like an audiobook chapter by Sam
Harris called The Last Time. I think
it's called The Last Time. And he
reflects on
these various experiences that at the
time you don't recognize are the last
time for something. Right? So, he he
went skiing, he went skiing, he went
skiing, and there was a time when he
stopped, but he didn't realize that was
going to be the last time.
>> Right.
>> And you just [\h__\h] don't know.
>> Do you ever try and like, I think about
this, dude, and then I try and do it one
more time.
>> Yeah, that's how I always end up
injured.
>> Dude, so I went to the bouncy house with
my kids and like I'm 49, you know, and I
was like, I'm going to [\h__\h] do a flip
right now. And like literally people
were like, don't do it. Don't like they
called me off, you know, and I did it
and I stuck it and it felt good.
>> You're good on a trampoline.
>> It was my last time.
>> It might be your last time. You are good
on a trampoline. This is so weird, man.
Dude, I kid you not, I had a dream last
night
of the two of us going to House of Air
at Crissy Field in San Francisco and you
were doing like front flips off your
knees, you dropped your hat and then you
like kicked the trampoline to bounce it
back up to your head and I was like,
what?
>> wait, wait, so you know I sent you that
video of me dropping my hat and kicking
back in my head.
>> live, too.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, so it just made its way into the
dream.
>> And I was just like, what? I literally
had that in my dreams last night. That's
wild.
>> And I had the assless chaps on like I
normally do when you're
>> Yeah, you had the assless chaps on which
like depending on your angle can be kind
of awkward.
>> Yeah, exactly. Cuz you like doing the
straddle flip.
>> [laughter]
>> So it's a little awkward.
>> I've heard about these dreams before.
>> [laughter]
>> I know like
>> I always text him and Kevin I'm like, I
was thinking of you last night.
>> Yeah,
the chaps were back.
>> [laughter]
>> So what do you got, man? I mean, people
should check out
>> My hands are too sweaty cuz I'm thinking
about
death.
>> Yeah, and the chaps.
>> [laughter]
>> Wow, that's the perfect audio.
>> The
Well, the retreat was fantastic. I spent
5 days going really deep on my koan,
doing a lot of work on it.
>> Moo.
>> Which you can listen to Henry Shukman on
your podcast if people are interested
about what Zen is all about, like real
true traditional Zen with koans and
you probably heard that sound of one
hand clapping. That actually is a one of
500 plus koans. Yeah, it was fantastic.
I had a couple little micro insights
which was good and I was kind
[clears throat] of rushed through to the
Zen master to explain them and try and
get some clarity on them which was
great.
>> How do you know that you're having a
micro insight? So it's not like my balls
are chafing in this position. It's
something else.
>> Yes.
>> [laughter]
>> But, close. No, I essentially was
sitting and
you know, Henry, one of the Zen masters
that you've had on the show,
dear friend of ours, was there. And then
his Roshi from Japan was there. So, it's
very special. And then he comes every 2
years.
>> What's his name? Yamada
Yamada Roshi?
>> I call him Roshi. Yeah. So, basically, I
was kind of pulled Henry aside. You're
not supposed to do this. Not talking,
but I was like He's like, "Yeah, how's
it going?" Like this and that. And I was
like, "Well, I had this thing happen.
What do you think about this?" And he's
like, "You got to come with me right
now." Well, not come with me, but he
like got me right in front cuz there was
a line to see the Roshi to go have your
private interview where you go and like
check your practice with him. Yeah. So,
it's behind closed doors. You go in. You
sit down with the Roshi. You typically
get between 2 and 10 minutes to sit down
and talk about your progress on your
practice. And you do that like, you
know, once every day and a half when
you're out there.
>> Mhm. That's cool.
>> Enough to where Henry was like, "You
should go talk to him right away."
>> Skip the line. TSA precheck.
>> "Just go through the precheck." And it
was beautiful. And it was a it was a
micro little thing.
>> I can share it if you're curious.
>> Yeah, of course I'm curious.
>> Yeah, so I'm sitting there waiting to
hear myself talk. That's why I'm here to
talk to you.
>> I'm sitting here staring against the
wall because in Zen you stare against
the wall with your eyes open. And you're
staring about 3/4 down kind of just
glancing on. I'm working on my koan. And
for people who don't know how you do
that is essentially on the out breath
you just slowly internally
say your koan. It's almost like a mantra
in some sense, but a little bit more
>> involved. Confounding.
[clears throat and snorts]
>> Yeah, it's like a question you're kind
of asking yourself slowly that doesn't
make sense. And eventually it pops. But,
what happened is
I had about 2 seconds of this sense that
there was
and this is going to be hard to explain
because it's not from the world of
thought, which are is already hard to
explain.
>> It's like a sneeze in the perineum.
>> No.
>> All right.
>> Close. I had a sense of nothing lacking.
>> Mhm. That sounds nice.
>> Nothing needed to be added and nothing
even possibly could be added and nothing
possibly could be taken away.
Because everything
at that moment
was full in the way that it should be.
>> Mhm.
>> But what was interesting about it is
it wasn't an emotion. It was just like a
steady state of being.
So it wasn't like, "Oh, I feel free
right now." No, none of that.
It was just like, "Oh,
this everything is here
perfectly present.
And it was just
wild.
>> Wild in what sense? In the
felt sense of that experience or
>> Wild in the sense that
>> Wild in the I just drank too much
tequila after not having much
>> I haven't had any tequila, but in the
sense that we often times so often like
go inside in in our into our brain
to try and find
something. Figure something out.
An emotional state that's either
bothering you or feels good or feels bad
or something else. And then just to know
that everything
and I don't mean like objects.
Everything was one
unit of nothing lacking.
>> Mhm.
>> And it was just a micro sense of kind of
like, "Oh, there's actually nothing to
do."
Because everything's already here.
>> Yeah.
>> And they talk about this in Zen a bit
where you already have everything that
you need.
>> [laughter]
>> Mhm.
>> So it's just they call it the removal of
the veil. So it's like it's an expansive
awareness that you get from
a deep continued practice over years and
decades.
>> Mhm.
>> But it was already there all along.
>> Can I give a shameless plug?
>> Yeah, let's hear it.
>> All right. So you and I are both
involved with The Way, which is this
guided single path meditation app,
which is guided by Henry Shukman who you
mentioned.
And it's the
such a progressive development of skills
on a single path, which I really like.
As opposed to just what is the
meditation de jour with no coherence.
>> Mhm.
>> And a few of my favorite meditations, I
have a lot of different sessions
bookmarked. I've done hundreds and
hundreds and hundreds. And by the way,
for people who are like, "Oh, these guys
are just selling their bags."
I do think it can be a good business,
but this is sort of a
ideologically philosophical
investment
>> Mhm.
>> of time and money.
>> Right. It's like the reason we invested
in the dog aging study with rapamycin.
It was like University of Washington,
it's like this needs to exist.
>> It exists.
>> It's good for the world. Let's try it.
>> Yeah.
>> So sure, we've got some chips on the
table, but this is this is mostly
because we believe in it.
And a few of my favorites, if people
ever try it,
Whole Earth is Medicine is one. Another
one is This Too Is Me, which makes me
think about what you're saying. So This
Too Is Me
is a meditation led by Henry, which
this is going to sound maybe esoteric,
but it's not. When you recognize that
all of the things you experience are
mediated by your mind.
>> Mhm.
>> Right? And therefore, like when you hear
something, when you feel something, when
you're interrupted by something,
etc., etc., anything you can possibly
imagine experiencing is also you because
ultimately
it is entirely mediated by your mind.
Let's just use that instead of brain.
>> [snorts]
>> And
it's incredibly, at least for me, and
I'm not comparing it to your experience
because I think it's probably
characteristically different,
is incredibly relaxing to let go, even
just for a moment. Because my brain is
like the ultimate
>> [laughter]
>> dog chasing a squirrel kind of brain,
right? Like I'm always looking for
something to fix, something to improve,
what I need to do, what is happening
next week. And meditation is You are the
squirrel. I am the squirrel. It can
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, right. It can be excruciatingly
painful, right? Like meditation can be
super hard. Super super hard. But when
Henry gives you
permission
to include all of that as you, I know
this might sound very bizarre,
it allows you to kind of drop this
burden that you didn't realize you were
carrying. So, in any case, you don't
have to do a week-long meditation
retreat. If you're just doing 10 minutes
twice a day, and I do think there's some
alchemy to twice a day.
I don't know why exactly. I have some
theories around vagus nerve stimulation
and stuff, but you get a lot out of it.
So, in any case, I didn't mean to
interrupt your story.
>> No, I think there's two things that I
love that Henry says quite often when he
starts some of these meditations, which
is
take everything that you came in the
door with, like all the thoughts,
worries, emotions, things, and leave it
at the door just for now. You can come
back to it in 20 minutes. But just for
now, the permission to set those things
down for yourself just for now is such a
beautiful thing. And then like the
little instructions where he's like,
"Drop your jaw an eighth of an inch."
And I'm like, "Whoa, I didn't even
realize it. I was clenching my jaw."
>> you something crazy about that?
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So, I got fitted for a
mandibular device, which is a fancy way
of saying a double decker mouthpiece.
Yeah, that is an easier approach to
resolving sleep apnea or snoring. So, I
don't snore a ton, but every once in a
while I do. Drives my lady insane,
understandably. And if you take the jaw
and drop it down an eighth of an inch
and forward an eighth of an inch, you
open your airway.
>> Mhm.
>> And I was thinking about that because
Henry will often say, as you're alluding
to, like drop your jaw and leave it
forward as if it's resting on a small
pillow, ever so slightly. And it
increases your air flow.
>> Mhm.
>> I mean, these ancients hit on some stuff
by trial and error
that really just works. It's like, yeah,
if you want to have better respiration
while you're meditating
and better alignment and blah blah blah
blah blah.
Just do it, Henry's describing. And I
will say his dulcet British tones.
>> Yeah.
>> If you just want a relaxing voice
>> that will help you with chilling the
[\h__\h] out when your monkey mind is
ricocheting inside your skull, like try
Henry out. Like you can find free stuff
everywhere. I've had him on the podcast
a bunch as well as meditation Mondays
for a while,
which were these very short episodes of
guided meditations. In any case,
>> Yeah.
>> it's great. I've been so It's right
word. I mean, overjoyed is
sounds too dramatic, but I'll just say
happy for you to watch your path with
meditation cuz it seems like you get so
much
nourishment and grounding from it. And
no offense, like you're kind of a spaz.
>> [laughter]
>> You're kind of spaz. Like you get
excited about [\h__\h] and then you drop
stuff that is very well exemplified and
like, "Tim, you got to buy this stock."
And then you never tell me when you sell
and I'm like, "Oh, [\h__\h] I'm fucked."
>> Oh, you want to talk about
>> Hold on. Hold on. No, no, no. Okay.
>> [laughter]
>> Cuz you lost
win.
Yeah.
>> You should have held. It's fine.
>> No. But anyway, literally Tim gives me
this tip and I'm like, all right, I'm
in. And then like a day and a half later
I'm down like
>> I know. That's why you got to wait. But
the point of the story is I thought this
meditation thing, just like every 9
months you're like, I'm moving to
Android. And I'm like, yeah, let me
start the timer for 2 weeks before you
come back to Apple. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> I'm like, yes, meditation thing. Yeah,
sure. We'll see. I give it 2 weeks. And
you've stuck with it.
>> Coming up on 5 years now.
>> Yeah. It's really made me
happy as your friend to see something
that gives you that
consistency.
>> Mhm.
>> That's it. There's nothing more to add.
I've been really What's the right word?
Not sure of the right way to put it.
I've just been very reassured
>> Yeah.
>> by you having that constant in your
life.
>> One of the things I'm curious about,
speaking of constants and kind of I
can't how things changed since we've
known each other and you had hair and
all that other [\h__\h] My hair wasn't
great.
>> got plenty of hair. It's not on my head.
Yeah.
>> Yeah, exactly. [laughter]
The braids down there.
The The question I'm I'm I'm curious
about is
I've been thinking a lot lately as I I
kind of march towards 50.
What are the things that I've always
said that I want to do
that I'm just like, you know, I've got a
thousand bookmarks on Instagram, like
all these Japanese woodworking things
and like
>> Little little always woodworking. Well,
I got you got to have the You know what
it is? How bad of my Speaking of the
monkey mind and bouncing around. I
literally have, for some reason, the
algorithm is now giving me like those
[\h__\h] boats inside of bottles,
people making the boats in the bottles.
I'm like, am I going to be a boat in the
bottle guy? Like, I don't know, maybe.
Like, I realize now, I think the next
couple decades
I want to stop bullshitting myself and
stop saying like, hey, one day. One day
I'll get into Japanese woodworking. One
day I'll do this. and really start doing
some things.
>> Yeah.
>> You've been really good cuz you archery,
hunting, like the stuff that you've
gotten into, you've gone deep on the
last few years.
>> Yeah, super deep.
>> Are there there any things that are on
your kind of bucket list of things where
you say one day, you know, you're busy
with your podcast and all the other [\h__\h]
you got going on?
>> shoot me in the head. It's [laughter]
It's fine and it's fun most of the time,
but it's so crowded and it's like, man,
if if 20 other people are trying to do
the same job, I don't want to do this
job. Yeah.
>> It is wild how many new podcasters there
are out there.
>> Well, also and they're also optimizing
every little freaking thing.
>> All the thumbnails and stuff like, what
you need to know before your crypto
crashes next week now and I'm like, God,
this
>> Yeah.
>> I just don't want to play that game and
for me, I would say the most top of mind
is rock climbing, actually. I just did
some outdoor rock climbing a couple days
ago and I love rock climbing. I was
always for at least the last 15 years
limited by my right elbow, which I had
surgically repaired, so it's ready to
go.
And I want to do some multi-pitch stuff
in Yosemite.
>> Dude, let's go.
>> Yeah.
>> So
>> I don't know if I want to say this.
>> [laughter]
>> All right, that's a good start.
>> So, you know who's a big rock climber?
He's
>> Yeah.
>> And he goes he goes out to to Yosemite.
>> I'm sure.
>> We should go cuz he's invited me to go
up there and do some climbing.
>> who'd be good.
>> Apparently he's amazing, so and I'm
like, dude, I can't go do multi-pitch
with you in Yosemite. He's like, "Ah,
just come out, we'll have fun, blah blah
blah."
>> No, that's how you end up [\h__\h] We
need
>> [laughter]
>> Exactly.
I did multi-pitch when I was like 24 and
it was like three pitches.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> Like I didn't
I didn't [laughter] do Yosemite.
>> Yeah, I know. That's a commitment.
>> Yeah. So, the idea of having something
like that to strive for, having some
type of physical goal like that for me
is very helpful, because just
not dying, like training to not die
sooner than is necessary is not
sufficient for me. I'm just like that's
such a
depressing,
uninvigorating goal.
I'd much rather have something that has
a deadline, right? It's like, all right,
you need to be able to do X. In the case
of the archery, it's like Lancaster
Classic, here's the date. You need to do
this type of training and this type of
volume with this type of deliberate
practice
in order to be prepared to train and
then compete. Right? Okay.
Similarly, for something like a
multi-pitch, it's like, okay,
you can break that down, and I just
enjoy doing that stuff.
>> Dude, so let me ask you a question. The
number two, I don't know if you saw this
on my my story list. The number two
story I had was this guy Michael
Eckhardt. Do you know who
>> Tommy, no, no idea.
>> Oh my god. Okay, so Huberman and Rogan
and all these guys, they've they've
talked about him publicly about this
guy. He has won multiple pull-up world
championships.
>> Okay.
>> And dude, when you watch him do a
pull-up, he's kind of one of those guys
that can bring the bar all the way down
and do like the typewriter style.
>> like where you can walk with your feet
and [\h__\h]
>> all the calisthenics stuff.
>> Yeah, but he has a series of videos that
that teach you how to do finger strength
training. And I bought his course, and
I'm doing this right now. But you got me
into that wooden device.
>> The Nug.
>> Yeah.
>> So, dude, you got to watch his videos.
They're amazing. And seriously, Joe's
really into them. Like this guy is My
name is Michael Eckhardt. You can find
him on Instagram, and it's all about
grip strength, pull-ups, and he's not
big, but he's shredded.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> And I think when I think about like the
next 10 years, like I don't need to be
big big.
>> It's probably not
>> Right, especially for rock climbing.
>> Yeah, exactly. I mean, you need to be
lean, right? And strong. And that's what
I love about this. So, I'm I'm into I'm
doing these every single day. One, two
days in.
>> [laughter]
>> Just like
I'm getting into it, you know?
>> Tell us about the Nug, cuz that was
something you turned me on to.
>> I mean, I have it in my suitcase at the
hotel here.
It's just a simple little
wooden device. It looks like a very
large bar of soap with these different
indentations carved into the sides.
>> Like little finger indentations.
>> Yeah, exactly. So, you can use a
carabiner to connect it to say a cable
machine of some type in any gym.
And like you could use a loading pin and
all this that and the other thing and a
daisy chain, but let's put it that
aside. At a gym, you could use a cable
and connect it through the loop with
carabiner and work on your hand
strength.
>> And you brought this to Santa Fe when we
were out there doing that meditation
thing, yeah.
>> I did, yeah. I mean, it's literally
something small enough to slip into my
sweatshirt pocket, so it's easy to
travel with.
I always travel with that and a band for
multiple purposes for like something
like called DNS kind of core exercises
and I
>> Oh, yeah, I know DNS.
>> Yes, so I use a band for that and it's
incredibly easy to travel with. And then
a handful of other things, something
called Alpha Ball, which I use for
different types of kind of mobility.
It's the size of like a very large soft
soft ball. And all of this stuff fits
into the corner of a suitcase.
And then I'll do also
something that uh maybe we haven't
talked about called Abrahamson's, which
so
Abrahamson,
Emil Abrahamson, very well-known rock
climber on YouTube. And Abrahamson's
>> I'm writing this down right now.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> Abrahamson's are pretty simple. I mean,
it's partial body weight hangs in
different positions for 10 seconds on,
50 seconds off for 10 minutes. And you
do that twice a day.
And it's very, very moderate in
intensity.
>> With like a wooden kind of rock climbing
kind of like type
>> could use a a hangboard.
>> Hangboard, yeah.
>> I mean, you could also use a pull-up
bar, depending on how you position your
hands.
And that's what I was doing in Santa Fe.
Was that kind of stuff. 10 seconds on,
50 seconds off. And
the endurance and strength gains that
you get in your hands just insane.
You're I should say your lower arms.
And
it really helps. So, I've been doing
indoor climbing, but ultimately I'm
like, "You know what?
As a stretch goal, multi-pitch outdoor
Yosemite."
>> Yeah.
>> And I am deadly terrified of heights.
Deadly Like just talking Like look I
don't even need to just look at my
hands. Like I'm sweaty just talking
about it.
>> Dude, when I watched Free Solo my hands
were sweating the entire time.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> For people who haven't seen that
documentary, even if you're not into
rock climbing, that is amazing.
>> Yeah, watch Free Solo. It'll freak you
out. So, that's one that I'm thinking
about going deep on. I'd say that's very
high up on the list because
>> dude.
>> We're going to be in the
>> Let's do the together. I can come with
you. I'm totally down.
>> down. I'm into it. I am totally into it.
I mean, rock climbing when approached in
a reasonable way, like a systematic
reasonable way, not with like crazy dyno
movements on bouldering necessarily. I
mean, look, younger bodies can handle
it. Certain bodies can handle it. My
body
not so much.
>> Yeah.
>> I do not want to fall repeatedly from 10
15 ft up. I'm just not into it. So,
in the case of doing it reasonably
though, for instance, I spent a bunch of
time I've spent a lot of time in Utah
and climbing in some of the Salt Lake
City indoor gyms, you have incredible
athletes.
And I'll I'll make that a little finer
tuned.
When I would go to the gym, it was
generally like 11:00 a.m.
Right? Who the hell goes to the rock
climbing gym at 11:00 a.m. on a weekday?
These are retirees
>> Mhm.
>> and moms. So, you would see, for
instance, these like 60 70 75, almost
80-year-olds who were doing like 5.11
plus.
>> This is when you were single, so that
was like prime hunting.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, exactly. Cougarville. And
you would just see these people in their
60s and 70s doing things that I could
not even imagine doing with complete
inversion on overhangs.
Like 60, 70 ft up, you had the national
speed climbing team, you had Olympians.
But more than like the young guns,
right? The 15-year-olds who are doing
all this crazy stuff because they're
impervious.
>> Yeah.
>> It was the people in their 60s and 70s
who were climbing every day that
inspired me to want to take this more
seriously. So I was like, "Okay,
I want to play the long game here.
What can I do that's fun?" It's a
puzzle. You use a lot of Tetris.
>> They'd literally call bouldering they
call problems.
>> Yeah, problems. Yeah, exactly. And so
there's a lot of brainpower involved.
And also it's just to give an idea of
the technicality. I mean, there are for
example women who cannot do five
pull-ups
who can climb 5.13, 5.14. That's very,
very, very, very, very hard just for
people who have no reference point. Like
world-class like 5.14, 5.15. Like
insane, insane. Like that's when you're
in the magazines.
>> Oh, 100%.
>> And it's because of sort of the
technical deftness. And yeah, there's
like ape index and other physiological
factors that play into it, but
that is a very long answer to your
question
of what I'm thinking about now, which is
rock climbing. The archery was great and
the competition was fantastic. I love
competing. However, archery is by
definition incredibly solitary. Like
you're just by yourself doing the same
thing over and over and over again
thousands of times.
And
I've had enough of that in my life. I've
hit my quota.
I want to hang out with other people. I
want
>> climbing is super social cuz you sit
there and you if neither of you can do
it, you'll you'll be like, "Ah, like
what if you put your like foot in like
that and like kind of lunged up that way
and stretched?" You know what I mean?
Like
>> Yeah, and then you can ask other people
for tips, like beta, right? Like, "Can
you give me some beta on this?"
>> It's fun. It's really fun. I just love
it.
You know, I wanted to mention something
if people haven't read it.
The Blade Itself, which is a series.
It's not very long. I think it's two or
three volumes by Joe Abercrombie. It's
fantasy novels. They're really good. The
audiobooks are incredible. And the
reason I thought of this, The Blade
Itself,
is because of our conversation around
Owen and Toaster and, you know, a friend
of mine just died in a plane crash.
>> Jesus.
>> Less than 2 weeks ago.
>> that the NetJets one that went in
Oh, you knew him?
>> Yeah, Josh.
>> Oh god, that was a Latitude, too?
>> Yeah, I know. I know. I know. So, you
just don't know when your time is up.
And in The Blade Itself, I mean, there
are a lot of [snorts]
>> Sorry, that sucks.
>> Yeah, thanks. And we weren't like super
close friends, but certainly like
friendly, you know, like acquaintances.
Like we wouldn't be strange to text.
And you just don't know when your time
is up. And The Blade Itself explores
this in a million different dimensions.
It's really, really outstanding. I've
read a lot I say that as someone who's
read a lot of fantasy.
And it just talks about the randomness
of life or death in war, right? It's
like you happen to like squat down and
take a [\h__\h] and the guy next to you gets
an arrow through the head. It's like,
it's just dumb luck.
>> yeah.
>> Which is a way to, I suppose, reiterate
the
gratitude piece that you were mentioning
earlier. So, I mean, that's going to be
a a tough act to follow, but
>> [laughter]
>> Where do you want to go from that?
>> Yeah, I mean, a few things. Let's change
it up a
Well, let's just go straight into like
working out. Have you tried this?
>> Yeah, I have actually.
>> Okay, I really like it. So for people
that are on audio, I just got turned on
to this new protein called Pioneer
Pastures and it's 30 g in this little
tiny shake. It's A2, so it has lactose
removed and it's also from that special
genetic cow. Do you know know more about
the A2? Can you speak to that?
>> heard about the A2. I don't know a whole
lot about it. It's like the Holstein and
some other cow and da da da da da.
Apparently
>> More people tolerate A2 better than not.
>> I don't get any stomach issues or
anything with this type of whey protein.
Anyway, I'm not an investor or any [\h__\h]
like that. You can get it at Target or
whatever. It's tasty as hell and it's 30
g and I don't know like I'm trying if
you're trying to put a little muscle
mass on.
>> I love this is next to the La La
Tequila.
>> Yeah, exactly. I mean you can mix them
if you want.
>> Everything a growing boy needs.
>> Anyway, I just I just wanted to know if
you had tried it cuz like we always This
is the random show. We do random [\h__\h]
>> I tried it.
>> You like it?
>> I do. Yeah, there was a gym I can't
remember exactly. I think it was
Brooklyn Barbell Club where they sold
this and I tried it then and I did.
Yeah, tolerated super well. Didn't get
the grumpy guts
>> Yep.
>> as one might.
>> What's your favorite protein out of
curiosity?
>> I mean my protein, I mean this is a
softball pitch, but
>> Funny you should ask Kevin.
>> I mean look, I'm involved with this one,
but you know what? I It's like I always
disclose. Have you noticed how few
[\h__\h] people disclose what they're
involved with? They're like, "Yeah, I've
heard of this great thing. Oh my god."
And they never disclose they're
involved.
>> The fact that you can literally go to
jail for that [\h__\h]
>> No, I know, but the FTC doesn't enforce
that stuff. Anyway, I mean right now
like I'm traveling with Maui Nui as
usual. This one though is kind of
interesting.
I probably get 40% of my protein from
Maui Nui venison. This is wild harvested
axis deer from Hawaii which is a long
story there, but incredibly nutrient
dense.
>> I love this [\h__\h] and this is not an ad,
but I do have a hard question for you,
like a real hard question. And this is
how you know that it's not an ad cuz you
already know what I'm about to say.
>> Let's hear it.
>> Processed meat, nitrates
>> Yep.
>> linked to a lot of cancer and bad [\h__\h]
What are your thoughts on that?
>> This is very, very, very minimally
processed. So, you can get summer
sausage or the sticks. This is free of
most of that [\h__\h]
>> What do you think that is? Cuz it is
real. Like people that eat more like
nitrate processed, ultra-processed
meats.
>> if it's ultra-processed and the shelf
life is like 3 years, I would raise an
eyebrow and probably hit pause. So, the
fact of the matter is most of this stuff
that is minimally processed
almost definitionally is not going to
last very long on the shelf.
>> What do they mean by minimally
processed? When you see like a meat
stick, like what do you think about like
that versus is the amount of salt
content that creates the nitrate?
>> No, they don't. It's actually nitrates
are totally separate categories. So,
you're looking to I think an easy
heuristic for this is just shelf life.
All right, like how long would
>> How long are those uh
uh
>> Your eyes are going to be better than
mine. If you can read this size two font
on this, then you can tell me.
>> that.
>> Give it a go. I'll buy you some time. In
the meantime
>> 27 years.
>> No, just kidding. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> 25 years.
>> It doesn't say on here.
>> Yeah, it'll say somewhere on the box.
There we go.
>> Oh, 27 years by.
>> Yeah, 27. So, it's like less than 1
year, I think, actually looking at it
here.
>> Yeah, less than 1 year. Wow.
>> And what makes this interesting is that
this I give also Molly looks really good
for 12 years. Mhm. I give her probably
two or three of these a week. The way I
think of this, this is peppered 10. So,
there's a bunch of these different
sticks. Like every professional team you
can imagine uses these things in their
training.
But, this is made with wild harvested
venison, liver, and heart. So, it has
some organ meat in it. You do not taste
that. It just tastes like regular jerky
stick. But, I treat this like a
multivitamin. So, it's I take
let's call it two or three of these a
week and limit it to that and then the
rest of the time I'm taking their other
either peppered or regular sticks. But
this is when I'm on the go. I mean
literally this was in my bag when I got
here, right? When I'm on the go, I'm
traveling with this, probably some nuts
of some type like pistachios and
whatever. Walnuts pretty good for a a
host of reasons. And
that's about it. I mean I might have
a couple of servings of exogenous
ketones, but I haven't taken that stuff
in a couple of months.
>> You told me you freaked me out. It
messes up your liver.
>> This is a controversial topic. So yeah,
there are certain
>> [laughter]
>> exogenous ketones that contain something
called 1,3 butanediol. It's very common.
And there's a lot of debate around this.
So the jury is still out, but some
people believe that that can
produce liver toxicity.
So I consume anything with 1,3
butanediol in moderation. Now to play
devil's advocate to a counterpoint, a
lot of the people who are putting forth
that hypothesis or claiming that's true
are selling their own ketone salts. So
they're actually selling a competitive
product.
>> I see. I see.
>> So question mark, question mark. But I
mean look, you can look at the
peer-reviewed literature and decide for
yourself.
What I have decided personally is that
you should use the exogenous ketones
very intermittently. I have experimented
a lot with every type of exogenous
ketone you can imagine.
>> I mean you got me on that good [\h__\h]
It's expensive as hell, but like that
stuff goes straight to your head. The
one that you didn't want to talk about.
>> We can talk about it.
>> You know what's funny is like when Tim
This is how you know it's good. Off
camera Tim's like, "I don't want to
mention the brand because if I do it'll
sell out and I won't be able to get my
own supply." And that's how I knew I was
like, "That's some good shit." If Tim
wants to the his own supply of it, like
you know it's good.
>> Yeah, and it is good, but it's BHB
I won't get too much into the
technicality here, but
it's beta hydroxybutyrate bonded to
1,3-butanediol. So, you're still getting
that 1,3-butanediol,
which means you should take it in
moderation, but
in a pinch, when you want to for a
podcast or something like that, man, it
really works.
>> work.
>> It really works, and I mean, I've given
it to relatives with dementia,
and within 20 minutes, their sentences
have like 5x in length, and they're more
acute verbally. It's wild.
>> How do you give it? I wish they had it
in pill form, because in some sense,
it's really hard to give that to someone
that has dementia, cuz it's like it
tastes like gasoline. It doesn't taste
great. It's not the worst thing. I mean,
I've had a lot of foul stuff in my life.
I just did a shot with this person, and
I was like, "I'll do it with you." And
then we went for a walk, and that was
it. There are some concerns around
1,3-butanediol
and
balance.
So, particularly in older adults, you do
not want to contribute to any risk of
breaking a hip.
>> Yeah, 100%.
>> That's just the death knell for a lot of
people.
>> I just had to put my mom into a
different home. It's actually kind of
cool. It's sad, but it's she's been
falling, and they have this like like
new AI orb that sits up there, and it
kind of does like a kind of radar type
situation, and it detects falls.
>> Oh, wow.
>> second she falls in the home, like they
can rush in and like help her out and
all that. And they they carpet the hell
out of it now and stuff like that. So.
>> How do you think about sort of
pre-grieving that or contending with
that yourself?
>> In terms of
>> family, that's rough. I mean,
>> Yeah, I mean,
>> it doesn't sound easy.
>> Cuz if you like play forward the tape,
right? It's like I mean, I think about
this with my own parents, and it's just
like nobody nobody lasts forever. It's
one of those things where it's so funny,
cuz when you're a teenager, and I
remember when my dad was having a hard
time standing and this was like when I
was much younger before he passed and
I was like, "Oh, dad's going to be in
like the thing that I might have to like
push him on it if he has to sit down."
Kind of those walkers that can also be
something you can push somebody on. I
was so embarrassed, you know? I was
like, "Oh, other people are looking at
us or whatever." And now I like push my
mom with pride in her walker thing and
I'm like
I don't know. You don't know when it's
going to what's going to happen, but the
only thing you can do is just make sure
to show up, you know, and hang out.
>> Yeah.
>> And and I'm very lucky that
my mom has dementia, but it it is a type
that
is not Alzheimer's, so it's probably
vascular or something. So, I can walk in
and she knows who I am. She can't tell
you what she had for breakfast, but she
knows who I am, which is like I'll take
that all day long, for sure, you know,
so
>> Yeah.
>> I know you have family members that are
in the same boat, which is just freaking
tough.
>> a ton of family members with
Alzheimer's. I mean, literally got a
call from one of my relatives wanting to
discuss interventions and
it's a tough conversation because there
really isn't much. Like you have to
as far as I can tell, act preemptively,
which is why actually this relates to
another bullet of mine.
>> Do you have five?
>> What was that?
>> How many bullets did you have?
>> Oh.
>> [laughter]
>> How many bullets do you have?
>> That was good. This is good. Of all of
all the rye whiskeys, it's the only one
that I can tolerate. I
loathe stationary bikes. I just I I
really find stationary biking to be one
of the most soul-crushing things in the
world.
>> worst.
>> However,
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, I've tried Peloton and didn't
like their ergonomics and so on for a
bunch of reasons.
And then I have tried very expensive,
very very expensive setups recommended
to me by fancy doctors and so on, which
are just like too uncomfortable. Like
I'm incredibly hunched over. Like my
back is basically parallel with the
floor.
>> What are you talking about?
>> And I'm like kneeing myself in the
stomach. It's so uncomfortable.
>> machines? What are you talking
>> I'm talking about getting on like a
stationary bike, but if you're like a
wasting position,
you have to adopt this hunchback and
like there are a million reasons why I
find that uncomfortable. There is a
bike, however,
it's very easy to find. It's pretty
common in public gyms, called the Keiser
M3i studio indoor bike. I don't know why
they have to make it so difficult in its
nomenclature, but the Keiser M3i is
unique in my experience in that you can
elevate the handlebars enough to sit in
a comfortable position with a decent
saddle, meaning the seat, such that I
can do the V2 and the V4 and all of that
training for me in a comfortable
position without compromising my low
back, which has been a huge step
forward. So, this is the only bike that
I've used consistently
for this kind of training and I was
having a number of conversations with a
neuroscientist named Dr. Tommy Wood over
a period of weeks and if for instance
you do something called the Norwegian
4x4, there's data to suggest that if you
do
it's VO2 max training, so it's very,
very, very intense, but it's like
>> Four on, three off.
>> Four minutes on, three to four minutes
off. Let's just call it three minutes.
Four minutes on, three minutes off and
you do that for four rounds. This is the
only bike that I've been able to use to
do this consistently and if you do that
for I think it's three times a week
for five to six months
the
volumetric changes, meaning the
neuroanatomical changes in the
hippocampus and other areas that are
certainly indicated in things like
Alzheimer's, lasts for up to five years.
>> Wow.
>> So, if you do five to six months of
gutting it out three times a week
>> Holy [\h__\h]
>> the dividends pay off for it seems up to
or possibly beyond five years.
>> Holy [\h__\h]
>> Crazy.
>> Wow.
>> Throw in some sauna in there and you're
like good to
>> Well, that's why I'm doing Yeah, I'm
doing all the usual stuff, right? I'm
doing the sauna and
don't let perfect be the enemy of good.
You know what I mean? It's like, okay,
sure, you don't have 30 minutes to do
it. Like do 10 minutes. Like you can't
do a sauna, take a hot bath. Like
>> Yeah. Figure it out.
>> You know what my good is that I like?
>> What's that?
>> It's not perfect, but it's good, which
is I go on my treadmill. I set it to
4.75
or something incline. Yeah. So it's like
not crazy, but it's not, you know, you
can still do [\h__\h]
>> Yeah.
>> And I set it to only like 2.5 on the
walking. Yeah. And I'll
play Duolingo chess, cuz they have chess
on there now for Duolingo. They teach
you chess. It's amazing. And you can
play friends and live people and all
that stuff. And they do game replays and
they teach and I'm learning a ton.
>> Yeah.
>> And 30, 40 minutes go by and you're
drenched in sweat. I know it's not high
intensity and all the benefits on the
the cognitive side seem to be around
like a lot of high intensity. Yeah, but
who knows? But it's good, right?
>> So it's something.
>> It's doing something, right? So I've
really enjoyed that. Like if you if you
just want something to both be like
learning and engaged and kind of like
having fun, yeah, so you forget about
the time. Do you know what I'm talking
about where it's like you just like, oh
wait, what time is it? Oh [\h__\h] I've
been on for 37 minutes. I can get off
now, you know? Like I love that type of
cardio.
>> Yeah, I mean, for me, I mean, this is
this is going to sound like maybe a step
down, but it's like the older I get, the
more I realize
a little goes a long way. Like
yesterday, for instance, I had a bunch
of stuff stacked up and I won't bore
people with the commitments, but
I didn't really have any time to go to
the gym and it was my day to go to the
gym to do X, Y, and Z exercises. And I
went in and I did three sets. I was
literally in there for 5 minutes and I
left.
>> Mhm.
>> But it's better than nothing.
>> Right. Totally.
>> Something is better than nothing.
I'm not going to go to the Olympics with
that approach, but let's [\h__\h] be
real. I'm not going to
wear lipstick.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean maybe he's like a bystander like
he's like in the
>> Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Oh man. So, I'll throw some new random
stuff in there.
The study that got my attention has been
it's been out since 2025,
September 2025. This is in JAMA.
And this is the title. Single treatment
with MM-120 and then in parentheses
lysergide, I think is how that's
pronounced, in generalized anxiety
disorder. Gad. The gad. [laughter]
This is a randomized clinical trial
looking at anxiety.
Which is often comorbid meaning
happening at the same time as
depressive disorders. And I think this
is sponsored by a company called
Definium which used to be MindMed.
>> I know where this is going. I just
looked it up.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah, well, what's interesting about
this and they're not going to maybe love
my comparison, but so MM-120 lysergide,
I mean it's
comparable to LSD.
>> Mhm. Right.
>> And this is a multi-arm clinical trial.
They did five arms which is rare to do
because the risk is that they'll blend
together. So, the arm means a group who
has is treated with a different
intervention in this case. So, they've
got placebo, 25 micrograms, 50
micrograms, 100 micrograms, and 200
micrograms. 100 mics
>> This is what they give
>> standard for LSD.
>> That's
>> That's what you can think of as a
standard hit, yeah, 100 micrograms. And
the results are wild, man. If you look
at the HAM-A score, this is up to 12
weeks out, you can see, I'll just show
you, how
>> [clears throat]
>> it's dose-dependent. The more you take,
basically, the better it goes up to and
I'm not sure how long the follow-ups
continued, but where you land is you see
that like the 100 micrograms and 200 are
very, very close together.
Like 25 and 50 are certainly a a lot
higher.
>> Now, are you still getting the same
psychedelic experience
with this stuff or
>> case of this particular compound, I
don't know. My guess would be yes.
I could be totally wrong in that, so
Tiffany, I'm feel free to correct me.
I am guessing the answer is yes with
MM120, but
what that says to me is, "Hey, 12 weeks
of relief
with GAD, generalized anxiety disorder,
which I've been clinically diagnosed
with, that and OCD.
Like 12 weeks is pretty good. And it
seems like, at least according to the
data in this study, the minimum
effective dose would be 100 micrograms.
Now, 100 micrograms,
at least for me and for a lot of people,
you'll be tripping your balls off, not
to get too technical.
>> Wait a second. Dude, it says that this
was done at Neuroscape at UCSF.
>> Was it really?
>> Adam's lab.
>> No [\h__\h] Are you serious?
>> I'm dead serious. I just clicked through
on it. It says phase three trial of
MM120 for GAD.
>> Oh, that's amazing.
>> trial. This is our buddy doing it.
>> This is our buddy Adam. Okay. Well, I
have a text that I need to send then.
>> Oh my god.
>> That's awesome. I wonder if I indirectly
funded this cuz I helped fund some of
Neuroscape stuff. That's funny. I did
>> Isn't that hilarious?
>> Yeah, I did not look at that. That's
hilarious. Small world.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> There you go.
>> So, you know, it's interesting for GAD.
We were talking about dementia.
There's a case report with high-dose
psilocybin mushrooms. I don't think it
was actually psilocybin synthesized.
Looking at this particular thing, it was
a Japanese elderly woman with dementia,
maybe an Alzheimer's, who
took I can't believe they did this to
her.
>> 5 g, right?
>> Yeah. And then she took 5 g, so Terence
McKenna heroic dose. Somehow fell asleep
for like 19 hours
>> [laughter]
>> or something obscene,
>> Almost would be very, very worrisome if
you're the child of said parent wakes up
and then starts having like full
expositional conversations
in contrast with her previous
monosyllabic or or single word responses
to things. And it was transient, it
didn't last forever, but it raises some
very interesting questions. I've seen at
least some case reports also with LSD
producing similar effects and I've been
interested in this for probably a
decade. I've hypothesized this could be
the case. It's just like, do you really
want to give your parent like under what
circumstances is it ethical to give
someone hallucinogens? See, I could
never do that to my mom because she was
always anti all this stuff. Yeah. And
then the second God forbid they have a
bad trip. Like why would you want to put
them through that, you know? So it's
curious. I was sent something by someone
I won't mention, but a very interesting
case report on microdosing with LSD.
With someone with dementia.
Yeah. And in terms of similar to the
ketones,
not saying the mechanism is the same,
but producing
much more verbal fluidity. Right, going
from like,
"I'm good.
It depends." Right, I have relatives who
are limited to that now. Like they're
basically giving answers that are
non-answers. "Sounds good." Right, like
these things that you could use as a
reply to anything.
They're not necessarily grokking what's
happening.
To full paragraphs.
Right, which means to my interpretation,
it's like offline to online. It's a
really stark difference. Because with
the one-word, two-word answers, like you
don't actually know if they're
understanding what's happening.
Do you have some MM120 on you right now?
>> [laughter]
>> I don't. I don't. If I did, I'd probably
not take it necessarily.
If you see a weird cut in the the video,
and then we get infinitely smarter,
you you'll [laughter] know why.
>> here and there. Yeah.
>> Exactly. It's a flash, and all of a
sudden we're just like brain dead.
>> I would keep it probably to 20 mics or
below. We'll see.
>> But, you know, I found this pretty
interesting for for GAD especially, and
then for the dementia piece, but it
raises a lot of ethical questions. What
is ethical to use as a treatment in
someone who cannot give consent? Right.
>> Right. That's a tough, gnarly problem.
>> Right?
>> Yeah. Especially if you're dealing with
stuff that is not exactly prescription
medication.
>> Yeah, I mean, that's the whole thing. If
it goes sideways, you feel like an
[\h__\h]
>> Well, yeah. To put it mildly, yeah.
>> but if it's amazing and it gives you
another, you know, half day with a
parent or loved one, and you can full-on
have conversations, and they see you and
you see them in a way that you hadn't in
6 months like or a year, like that's
amazing, right? So,
>> Yeah. Or if it potentially slows the
decline.
Right? I I think it's too much to hope
for a reversal, frankly.
>> Yeah. But, there are some strange
phenomena out there, man. Like, there's
this
>> phenomenon called terminal lucidity,
where someone like on their deathbed,
when they've been vegetating off this,
and like they gradually Did you read
that?
>> I'm not sure.
>> book?
>> No, I didn't read that.
>> Okay, cuz they they talk about that.
This is well This is well documented,
where people suddenly they have been
basically vegetative, or
>> And like the last 2 days, they come
fully lucid. Yeah.
>> become totally lucid. They have
full-blown, extensive conversations.
>> That's why I know.
>> What the [\h__\h] is going on there?
>> Dude, I'm telling you, it is so weird to
me that we think like Like, a lot of the
things that we do in physical form, like
what we do in life, mimics nature in
many ways. And all of our data is like
backed up in the cloud. And we're like,
"Oh, we're not backed up in the cloud in
any way." And then there's these people
with like full-blown entanglements in
their brain, full-on, you know, the
Alzheimer's for like a decade and then
they become completely
lucid? Where is that coming from?
>> Okay, I see what you're saying. I wasn't
tracking that fully for a second. But if
I'm hearing you correctly, it's like if
it's all localized, now I'm saying like
if all of that ability is localized
within the confines of the skull,
>> Mhm.
>> how do you explain
>> Right.
>> this given all the structural
deterioration.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah, I don't have good answers for
that. I just don't. It is a
well-documented, as far as I know, a
well-documented phenomenon.
So it's like go figure that one out. I
mean, I'm not qualified, way above my
pay grade.
Crazy, man.
>> It's wild.
>> It is wild.
>> So I'll give a shout-out to somebody.
We're not going to open this right now
cuz we'll start chewing on them and
we'll be up all night. Is that the 120?
>> No, this is Nootropic.
n e u t r o n i c, nootropics.
>> See, that's a pun.
>> Nootropics cuz these are toothpicks that
I was given by
a podcaster you may recognize.
>> I think Chris Williamson and they have
like
>> They have like 20 I want to say 20. I
might be getting that off, but like 20
25 milligrams of caffeine in each
toothpick.
>> Oh, wow.
>> are a couple of other nootropics, aka
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, smart drugs in there.
And they're great.
>> You just like suck on a toothpick.
>> Because if I have cups of coffee, I will
chug a cup of coffee and then if it gets
refilled, I'll chug another cup of
coffee and it's a problem. These
actually is, in terms of pacing,
have been fantastic.
>> That's amazing.
>> So that's been my sort of not exactly
coitus interruptus for people to get
that, but
sort of
>> [laughter]
>> ad libitum interruptus. Yeah, avoiding
overconsumption of coffee and other
stimulants. This helps me to kind of
pace it cuz even if I chew on this thing
until it's fragments of wood, max I can
squeeze out of it is 20 25 milligrams.
>> Yeah.
>> What else you got, Kevin?
>> Yeah, I mean, the only other thing that
I have that I think is is interesting is
what's happening in the world of I don't
want to talk a lot about AI cuz I'm just
frankly AI'd out, but I will say that
the idea that we can all now kind of
take control of
our productivity and pretty much
anything that we want to control now
like device-wise.
We can do with just a few simple prompts
on AI.
And I had a buddy that came over to my
house and he was like, "Hey,
you got cameras in your house?" I have
something called Ubiquity which is like,
you know, like they have cameras and
there it's a very common kind of
household type situation when you want
to have security system, front door
thing, cameras, sensors, water detectors
underneath like things in case things
leak and you're out of town, whatever.
And so I've got this whole setup and
he's like, "Hey, you know, they have a
full-on API where you can just tell
Claude or whatever to code against it."
And I was like, "Okay, this is
interesting. Like, what can it do?" And
so the cameras now have AI sensors where
they can detect
who it is that's walking in.
So it's like, "Oh, Tim's coming up to
your door. Oh, that's your daughter.
That's your dog." What it detects my
dog, Toaster. Like sees him and it puts
like a little dog emblem above his head
when he's walking around and it knows
that it's Toaster. But the crazy [\h__\h] is
I was like, "Okay, well, what if I can
go further
and I can tell it to do actions cuz
there's a speaker hooked up to it as
well. So that's for security. So
basically if anyone loiters in my
alleyway and it detects it, it's like I
have I play some like really funky [\h__\h]
where it's like, "Detected like loiterer
in the alleyway." Like whatever and just
to scare people off in case they're
>> I am the Batman.
>> Yeah, but you could draw the areas
around where they shouldn't be which is
like at your door fiddling with your
door and say if they stand here for more
than 30 seconds, play set audio out of
speaker.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> So I I like, "Okay, this is interesting.
Well,
what if when I walk in my house, if I'm
wearing like a hat of like my favorite
sports team
and they're playing,
it like reads me the score as like I
walk in.
>> Mhm.
>> So, you can think about all these things
where it's doing stuff based on your
activity, right? So, like if you're out
there gardening, it'll be like, hey
Kevin, I noticed that the plant over
here wasn't watered enough or like So,
it's watching all of this stuff.
>> Yeah.
>> And so, there's a lot of
if-then-than-that kind of situation.
Like, if I see you doing X, so like the
latest I have is I programmed it so when
it sees the license plate on my car,
>> Mhm.
>> it automatically knows to open the gate
cuz it knows it's me.
>> Yeah, yeah. That's cool.
>> camera looks at the license plate on the
freaking car, checks it against the
database, and allows me in. How crazy is
that?
>> Yeah.
>> And for people who are listening, I'm
not talking about $10,000 systems. The
camera is like $200.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> Anyone can do this at home, you know?
And it's just wild to think about
Finally, we had all these these kind of
discrete systems that, you know, were
you had some Nest stuff and I had some
Google Home stuff. Now, they're all
talking to each other.
>> Uh-huh.
>> So, you can just do kind of really crazy
I know you would like this because
you're the kind of person that you've
told me before like you don't like to
answer your door
cuz if the delivery person is like,
"Tim!" Then all of a sudden your address
is called over the internet.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, I mean, I know you said you don't
I'm also pretty AI'd out, but at the
same time, it's like
I can't I can't resist going back to the
opium den. It's so fascinating.
>> you doing now with the with the AI
stuff?
>> Well, I mean, I'm more curious to hear
your thoughts and predictions, frankly,
because I think you're better at it, but
I mean, I'm using
Claude code with various APIs to do tons
of like inbox analysis and stuff. Right?
I'm doing a 20-year
retrospective analysis of angel
investing.
>> Mhm. It's like, who made what
introductions? Which companies did I not
reply to that ended up being successes?
Which did I
turn down that ended up being
really important.
>> really want to do that to yourself?
>> Well, I suspected it'd be worse than it
was. I actually have not I haven't
missed that many explicit opportunities.
I wanted to test my own stories against
data, right? Cuz I have all sorts of
stories
>> Right.
>> about why I did certain things and why
certain things worked out. And I have
certain stories about my
batting average. And I'm like,
but is it true?
>> Right. Really.
>> Is it really true? Let's look at some
hard numbers.
>> The sad truth and I have a buddy that
wears that the bracelet and you've seen
me with the necklace where on the
categorizes your AI and listens to you
24/7.
>> Yeah.
>> It's about 70-ish percent that we think
we know, but is actually what we know.
>> Yeah.
>> Out of the 100% of like what we think we
know, this is the truth. I said I wanted
a dark chocolate bar at 7:00 p.m.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like, nah, you said it at 5:00 and
you said it this way.
>> And you said it was milk chocolate.
>> Yeah, exactly. So, it's always about 20%
off from where you actually think your
brain's at.
>> Sure.
>> Which is brutal.
>> Well, plus, I mean, that's like last
week, right? If you're talking about
like 15 years ago.
>> I mean, if you listen to the any genesis
story of any startup, you're like,
>> [screaming]
>> Oh my god.
>> Wait a minute now. Like, this is like a
startup comic working on material, but
he's been working on this one 5-minute
bit so long that now he believes that's
actually truth.
>> Yeah.
>> The I mean, the sanitizing and the
editing of these startup genesis stories
is hilarious, and there's no reason to
think that I would be or you would be
exempt from it, right? When you're
telling your own story, even if you're
just telling it to yourself.
>> So, what's the number one thing that
you've learned by applying AI to your
life in this fashion? Like, what's the
thing where you walked away and said,
"Damn, that was insightful and I'm going
to change my behavior, or I learned
something new about myself that I
wouldn't have if I had not used AI.
>> Well, I think from a holistic health
perspective, by holistic I mean
having enough data related to
medications, supplements,
predispositions, side effects, what
happened to me 2 weeks ago,
the LLMs have been incredibly helpful. I
mean, the picture that they get and the
speed with which they can deliver an
answer that I can interrogate is
incredible.
>> What did you learn? Like, what was the
thing that you learned?
>> I mean, honestly, it's mostly avoiding
disaster, right? It's like, are any of
these things contraindicated with one
another? Could A, B, or C explain D? And
you have to keep in mind these things
can still hallucinate, but
you can
I don't want to say eliminate that, but
minimize it by just fact-checking across
LLMs. There's that. I would say that
there's a lot of insight on, hopefully,
that I can translate to future
decision-making related to
investing, which investing for me is not
just amassing more chips. What's fun
about investing to me is it's a way to
scorecard your thinking and
decision-making.
>> Mhm.
>> It's just a very objective way
to decide if something was the right or
the wrong decision. And you can
fine-slice that, and there are ways that
you could maybe question that, but
if you're asking yourself, "Was I
thinking well last month?" That's not a
very helpful question. Where do you go
from there?
>> Mhm.
>> If you're logging maybe every decision
you make every day and then trying to
cross-reference outcomes with blah blah
blah, like, yeah, but you're never going
to do that.
>> Mhm.
>> But when you're making relatively
frequent investments, you can do that.
You can also run counterfactuals, right?
What if I did the opposite? What if I
had not sold that? What if I had kept
that? What if I had done this? What if I
had done that?
>> Is that worth your time, though?
>> At the end of the day, you can put
everything into S&P 500 and just go to
bed.
>> Well, there's that. I would say it's
worth it to me because I find it
interesting.
I actually enjoy the intellectual
exercise of it. But, otherwise, I would
say with
in terms of like how AI has has impacted
me,
I would say that
the honest answer is not that much
because most [\h__\h] isn't worth doing in
the first place. People are finding very
very clever ways to expedite
automating workflows of all different
types, and doing something well does not
make it important or worth doing in the
first place. So, there's a lot I think
the level of [\h__\h] that is being done
just at a very fast efficient rate is
skyrocketing.
>> Yeah.
>> But, simultaneously, there are
definitely cases where
I look back at, say, this analysis of 20
years of stuff.
To do that manually would be impossible.
>> Sure.
>> All right, it would take me a year
full-time with multiple people to do
that. And with a Claude code, Gmail API,
and
leaving my computer running for a
handful of hours a few times, that's
like what you get back is [\h__\h]
credible. Like, it's unbelievable, and I
haven't even scratched the surface.
>> Yeah.
>> I will say also another way that AI has
maybe affected my life in a
net negative way, and I'm not We have
another mutual friend who maybe we
shouldn't name, who feels very
similarly, is
>> [laughter]
>> We'll bleep that out, but yeah.
Jesus Christ. So, if you train
AIs on your writing,
they're really good.
>> Yeah.
>> And I think I feel This is a stretch of
a comparison, obviously, cuz I'm not
an adept like a world-class Go player,
but when AlphaGo defeated one of the top
Korean players.
>> Mhm.
>> He was kind of like, I'm done. Like,
Like, I don't find joy in this anymore.
>> Yeah.
>> If we're playing against machines.
>> And when I see these AIs very
beautifully, I'm not going to lie.
And they're we're like in the top of the
first inning, right? This stuff is going
to get so much better. Spit out stuff
that is so much better.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, I can still write, but what they
can do in 30 seconds is what would take
me 30 hours.
>> Right.
>> just like, [\h__\h] It really drains the
motivation for me to put in those 30
hours.
>> Yeah.
>> Why wouldn't it? Of course it would,
>> Right?
>> Yeah, but in some sense, you can
consider it a really good co-pilot
because for it to come up with novel
ideas that would engage an audience,
that's still the holy grail where it's
not quite there yet, right? Like, it's
going to make you sound it's going to
button up your copy.
And it might expand upon it in ways that
you wouldn't, but it's not going to come
up with the original thesis for the
whole thing, right?
>> Yeah, it's going to have trouble with
the original thesis, but even there,
I think it does a pretty good job.
>> Really? It's getting better. I haven't
tried with writing stuff, so
>> Well, if you just do a data dump and
you're like, create
>> Oh, oh, you sent me that link.
>> Yeah, if you if you just do a data dump
and you're like, create
>> sent me that link, you were like, what
should Tim do in the next 5 years or
whatever?
>> Oh, yeah, that was good.
>> That was really interesting. Tell people
what you did because like, they might
find this they could apply it to their
own life.
>> Sure. So, you could do this in whichever
model you're using, whether it's you
know, Copilot or ChatGPT or whatever.
If it knows you,
>> You can tie in your inbox, too.
>> Yeah, you can tie in your inbox. In my
case, I didn't do that, but if it has
enough history on you, you can just ask,
what do you think I should do in the
next 5 years? What might be some
rewarding paths of exploration?
>> Mhm.
>> I put something like that.
>> What are three to five ideas
that you think could be rewarding career
exploration for me in the next X period
of time.
>> So, for people listening, if if they've
used AI for let's call it 3 to 6 months
and you've probably given it several
hundred things to think about, it will
span across those conversations as long
as you turn this on. It's I think it's
on by default now, but it used to be an
opt-in thing where you have to say,
"Allow the AI to look across
conversation." So, it has a holistic
understanding of who you are.
>> And the answers were [\h__\h]
outstanding. Yeah. I mean, really,
really good. Yeah. And I sent it to a
few friends. Sent to you. I sent it to a
few of my closest friends and they're
like, "That's pretty [\h__\h] good."
Yeah. I mean, it was really cool. It's
some of the ideas I was like, "Damn, you
should do that, dude." You had this one
business idea for you to do and it
wasn't a book and I was like, "Dude, I
text you back. I was like, that's
awesome." Like, "Go go build that."
Yeah. There were business ideas. There
were certainly kind of non-revenue,
but philosophically aligned ideas. It
was shocking to me. So, that's actually
a very good example of something that
has deeply informed what I'm mulling
over as I imagine the future. I was
like, "Man, that actually is a really
good." Because, keeping in mind, I'm
asking questions about
things of interest, things I like,
things I don't like. I am asking
questions about
different scientific interests related
to Sci-Sci Foundation, my non-profit
foundation. I'm asking questions about
investing. I'm asking questions about
writing. I'm asking questions about
relationships. I'm asking questions
about organizing trips for friends. I'm
asking so many different questions. Am I
still on the board of your non-profit? I
think you're like secretary or
something. Yeah, something like that.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, I don't know.
Maybe you were honorably discharged. I
don't [laughter] know.
Yeah, well, I said it was going to be a
light lift. It's a light lift.
>> [laughter]
>> That's a very good example, right? I
mean that that may be the best example
because if that even 10% informs like a
major next chapter,
100% like that's a big deal for me,
certainly.
>> And it makes me think a little bit about
podcast listeners, especially. Readers
also, but to a greater extent podcast
listeners who come up to me
and most most listeners I run into are
really great and not I mean there are
always a couple of weirdos, but most are
fantastic and they'll say something
often like, "I'm so sorry you don't know
me at all and I feel like I know you."
And what I say a lot of the time is
actually, "If you listen to my podcasts
every week or even every month, you do
know me pretty well."
>> Yeah.
>> And then you think about
a machine that never forgets.
>> Yeah.
>> It's going to know you pretty damn well.
>> Yeah, of course.
>> And it's spooky in a way.
>> Yeah.
>> But I started getting more out of the
LLMs
when I started asking questions and I
have to be I think a little careful with
outsourcing this
and absolving yourself of responsibility
to think about these things, but when
you ask it open-ended personal questions
in the way that you would ask a close
friend, right?
>> Mhm.
>> What do you think are three to five
creative ways I might explore things
professionally in the next five years?
>> Yeah.
>> As opposed to something that you think
is more suitable for a robot.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> You get some really interesting
responses.
>> That's a great use case.
>> Yeah.
>> The one thing I've been playing around
with lately that I haven't told you
about yet, but you know, I think about
all these AI startups and everyone
that's creating all these different apps
and all that stuff and for me, you know,
that's kind of fun to watch as a kind of
bystander being like, "Oh, cool. You're
going to make this."
But I I really want to explore things
that
just no one has done before. It's always
been interesting to me more than just
like iterative kind of like sanding down
a lot of the rough edges. A lot of
startups will go out there and be like,
"Hey, you know what sucks is
word processing doesn't do this, so I'm
going to like make a slightly better
word processor." I'm just making this
up, but
I like the kind of wilder, crazier, like
I'd rather have it fail and say I did
something new than just do something
boring.
>> Yeah. Oh, I get it.
>> And so lately what I've done is
>> so many fatalities.
>> So many of you died, [laughter] yeah.
Exactly. Same. What I've done lately is
I've taken
I went and bought a bunch of these decks
of cards on Amazon that are values
cards.
>> What does that mean?
>> Meaning like they give you like a deck
of a hundred things and they're like,
"What are your core values?"
>> All right.
>> And you're like empathy or kindness or
like you like flip through them and the
way they typically work is that you have
like a really high value, a medium, and
a low value. And then you put them in
different stacks. And then you walk away
and you say, "Oh, this is my high value
stack of things that are my core values
that mean a lot to me." And it might be
10 or 15 different cards, right?
And what's interesting is to do that
with like friends and partners and
things like that and then compare them
and say, "Hey, what do we align on? What
we don't align on?" And I can imagine
for like an intimate partner this would
be a a pretty important thing to do,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> And so I started there and I'm like,
"Okay, I'm well I'm going to scan these
cards in and then I'm going to pair it
down and make these core values where
you come in and say this matters to me."
And it's almost like a swiping like, you
know, dating app or something like yes,
I'm into
>> Yes, I'm into that. No, I'm not.
>> Yeah, exactly. But you swipe through
them and then when you're done with that
then you've got your list of like these
values and they can change over time.
And so I think the important thing is to
log that and say these are my values
today, but tomorrow one might shift a
little bit, right? And then I thought
about contractual bonds. And so So the
working title I have for it is just
called bond, and where I can say like
with a partner, I'm going to create a
contract with you where we both have to
shake on it. Meaning like a virtual
shake. You think of it of almost like a
SimCity like situation. This is my city,
this is her city, or a friend's city,
and we're going to agree that I take the
trash out every Tuesday night.
>> Mhm.
>> And there's an emotional shake on both
sides, and if I break this bond,
it results in what? And so from the
partner's side, it would result in a 1
to 10 on how much damaging this is to
me. So not taking the trash out probably
be like, "Ah, that sucks cuz the trash
is going to overflow." That's probably a
three to most people, right? And so then
I kind of get negative points in case I
break that bond. But what's interesting
though is that will link back to a core
value of theirs and a core value of
mine.
>> Yeah.
>> And I want [clears throat] to show up as
a good partner, and there'll be a core
value associated with that. And then you
could see those bonds between multiple
people. And the reason I say this is
because I've always been one of these
people historically that have said
>> Yes to so many things.
>> be a last minute. I'm the worst at that,
you know, where I'm like, "I'm in." And
then I'm like,
"I'm an introvert. I'm out." You know,
at the last minute, right? And so I just
think that there needs to be a system
where
almost like a LinkedIn for like values
and trust and bonds. There was a great
Wu-Tang quote that's like, "Word is
bond." And I always been like I really
believe that. Like there's something
really cool about saying, "You know, we
have the Better Business Bureau." That's
like the best we got, right? Like, "Oh,
this person they did well by their
customers
>> 2,000 times.
>> What about individuals in saying like,
"Hey, this person was always empathetic
towards me." Or this person was kind and
helped me move on a Sunday.
>> all this?
>> I don't know. I'm just thinking about
it.
Just like The thing I think about is
that there's
>> Well, I can't No, hold
>> No, hold on. Let me give you the real
answer.
I call this dark information.
>> Dark information.
>> Yeah. So dark information is information
that exists in the real world, but we
have yet to put in physical form.
>> Okay.
>> And so right now you and I have a trust
thing.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> You know that if the camera was turned
off, there's certain things that you can
tell me that you're pretty certain I
will not tell anyone else.
>> Right.
>> Every once in a while I do,
>> [laughter]
>> but you know where that line is, right?
But that hasn't been concretized in any
type of like visual real format.
>> Mhm.
>> And so there's something interesting.
I'm just brainstorming with you in real
time because we've had a couple of
drinks, but like my point is if there
was a system where I could say I've
created these bonds, I've built up this
reputation,
>> Mhm.
>> but it would also give me a way to
reflect back and be like, "Oh, you know
what? I can see now historically that
I've often bailed on events that I've
signed up for. Let me improve that in
myself, right?" The whole point of what
you brought up a minute ago was
if I use AI to go back historically and
look across things, I can detect these
trends and then make course corrections
based on those trends, right? And so
there's something interesting about this
idea of
there are these different facets so
there's these like emotional facets we
have with every individual, how might we
track those?
>> Well, what jumps out of me about this is
maybe a cool use case would be
identifying
you could write it out or you could have
cards, your values, but maybe to put a
finer point on it, the type of person
you believe yourself to be.
>> Right. But that's very different than
what people perceive you to be.
>> Or or the type person you want to be.
>> Right, exactly.
>> it's like, let's take a look at your
calendar and your email and your
iMessages to see how much your story of
what you think you are or what you want
to be matches up with your behavior.
>> So remember maybe 7 years ago you did a
360 review for me?
>> Yeah.
>> Those things are brutal.
>> For people that don't know what 360
reviews are is like you give 10 of your
friends to somebody,
they interview them,
they collect all the data anonymously.
>> Could could be like co-workers,
employees, bosses,
>> friends, whatever. And then you get a
report back being like, "Here are the
deficiencies and positives that this
person brings."
>> Anonymized.
>> Brutal.
>> And they are very different than what
you think you're how you show up.
>> And so like that's the idea.
>> was looking at mine from like 12 years
ago. A couple years ago and I was just
like I was just like
>> I know. So tough.
>> I know.
>> You get it back and you're like
>> Who said this?
>> I know.
>> Somebody
>> of his
>> Brutal.
>> I know what you said, by the way. Do you
ever use the word child rearing?
>> Child rearing?
>> [laughter]
>> Would you ever say that?
>> Child rearing? I mean
>> To throw me off, would you ever say
that?
>> To throw you off the scent trail?
>> Because before I had kids, somebody in
my anonymous 360 review said like, "Oh,
he's going to have a hard time with
child rearing."
>> know, that wasn't me.
No, that's not me. No, that's not me.
>> I don't have any friends that even have
that in their vocabulary. And I'm like,
the only person that could do that would
be Tim trying to throw me off with a
[\h__\h] smart-ass word.
>> wasn't me. That wasn't me. That
[laughter] wasn't me.
No, no. I think I'd be able to identify
whatever response that I gave.
>> That's the one thing that stuck with me
after like 15 years. I'm like, "Who the
[\h__\h] said that?" [laughter]
>> Man, you're lucky if you got off with
that. I've got so much more. Good lord.
You know what I've been doing
that has been really helpful
because the blank page is something I
struggle with with writing, which is
probably the reason why the AI is so
demoralizing in a sense because the AI
allows you within like 30 seconds, which
is like, "Boom. How you like me now? Try
to match that." But
using even though I certainly don't know
the future of this company cuz they
might get replaced by features that are
innate to X, Y, or Z, but WhisperFlow
>> Oh, god, I love it.
>> Yeah, so using WhisperFlow as a data
dump
>> I wish I was an investor in WhisperFlow.
>> may have recommended this to me, I can't
recall, but basically doing a dump of a
conversation as I'm walking with
WhisperFlow
>> Yeah.
>> into a note on my phone,
>> Mhm. then taking that, dropping into
Claude, asking it to like clean it up
and turn it into something readable has
been so helpful. Not necessarily for
publication, but for emails, especially
uncomfortable emails where you're like,
"Oh god." Like I just like I'm putting
it off and procrastinating cuz I don't
want to do it.
Just doing like a 10-minute brain dump,
it's shocking how quickly things come
together. Like incredibly helpful. And
I'll just give a shoutout to my friend
Alon Lee, co-founder of Exploding
Kittens. He recommended this headset cuz
I was on a call with him. I'm like,
"Man, that audio is awesome. What are
you using?"
>> Can you put it on just for the viewers
at home? Cuz it's it's going to look as
good as I hope it does.
>> It looks so good.
Yeah, it's pretty good, right?
So, this is the Shokz, s h o k z, Open
Commute UC, open-ear bone-conduction
headset. So, he was talking. I'm like,
"What the hell are you wearing?" I was
like, "Audio's really good." So, it
looks pretty dorky. This is like a
>> No, it's great.
>> [laughter]
>> And the bone conduction is right here,
effectively my cheekbones. And when you
first use them, you're like, "Wait a
second. I feel like this is playing out
of speakers. Like this is nonsense. This
is complete BS." But then you totally
plug your ears and you can still hear
perfectly well. Which is crazy.
And what I like about these is A, the
audio quality is great. And you know,
the connectivity varies, but the audio
quality is fantastic. You can hear. So,
if I'm like walking my dog, walking
Molly, and I want to be able to hear
traffic and so on, I can use this cuz I
especially if I'm using Whisper Flow to
data dump into a text file of some type,
I don't really need to be listening.
It's not like I'm on a phone call or a
Zoom call or something.
So, I find this very, very helpful so
that I can actually pay attention to my
surroundings.
And that's all I got. It's basically
this and AirPods. I mean, there there
are other headphones that I will use for
professional recording and stuff.
But
thus far, I'll I'll share one more tech
thing real quick. These this little
baggy here is the Sennheiser Pro Audio
Condenser Microphone. It's very simple.
I've just been very impressed with the
audio. When I'm on the road recording
stuff for the podcast like intros or
sponsor reads or whatever, it's just a
simple lav mic. It's so simple, but the
audio quality even in a hotel room that
is really bouncy, lots of glass, lots of
metal where it should sound terrible,
if I use a fancy
like this is a Shure mic that we have
right here. If I were to use this exact
mic cuz I have it at home.
>> Yeah.
>> In some of these bouncy rooms, it would
sound worse, I'm not kidding, than what
I get for my purposes
>> Wow. Crazy.
>> with this.
It's pretty wild. And I love Shure. I
use their mics on a lot of podcasts, but
in terms of minimizing bounce,
>> Yeah.
>> for whatever reason, this little baggy
that I can stick in a pocket, right?
It's like this is my portable
sort of
recording studio.
>> Have you recorded on the iPhone with it?
>> I have.
>> It sounds good?
>> great.
>> That's amazing.
>> And I don't have my phone with me. There
is
an app that you can use for really
high-fidelity recording. It's called
like Ferrite or
>> Yeah, it's like lossless recording,
right?
>> Lossless recording. It's like f e r r i
t e, something like that. I'll put the
link in the show notes for this for
people who are interested. The quality
is absurd. And you can also use Descript
or one of these programs to do AI
cleanup, and it's crazy.
>> Yeah, you didn't need You didn't
need Descript anymore. Like you can just
use all the models do it. Gemini's
actually quite good at it multi-modal
audio, video, all that stuff.
>> Uh, cool. Gemini, honestly, I've been
using
Gemini more and more just because it's
such plug-and-play with
with G Suite, also.
>> Yeah, I mean 3.5 Flash like is a great
model. Although the new Sonic just came
out and that's for men throbbing that
just came out and that's I haven't
played with it yet cuz it was literally
launched today and it's it's supposed to
be fantastic.
>> What do you think the landscape looks
like in a few years? You got Anthropic
and Open AI racing to IPO, see where
that goes. You've got Mythos / Fable
taking off.
>> Mythos is out tomorrow.
>> Right.
Right. Okay, was it national security
threat yesterday but it isn't today.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> What do you think? I mean, I think
>> It's the big three. It's three players.
It's Google, Anthropic and Open AI.
>> Mhm.
>> And X is trying and I would never ever
count out Elon. Obviously like he has
the funds to make it happen.
>> Well, also Anthropic and Google are
buying excess capacity from Colossus,
right?
>> Yeah, but that means that their product
isn't working.
>> Yeah.
>> Because they bought that capacity for
themselves.
>> Right.
>> So that means that no one's using Grok,
you know? I mean, I actually like Grok.
I use Grok more than people might
realize.
>> Here's what's interesting about it.
>> For current events and synthesizing.
>> Yes, so they have direct access to the X
API and they has actually X tools built
into Grok. So if you want to like get,
like you said, current events, news,
things like that. And they've also said
that it is one of the
most grounded models and doesn't
hallucinate. So that it's really good
at. And so on Dig, when we relaunch it,
we use a lot of AI to kind of come up
with the different stories and all of
that. We use it a ton because we want
that grounded information that is true,
you know? And so it's really important
to have that. And I I don't know. I
mean, I think I wouldn't count them out.
I should probably include them in that
list as is.
>> so big three. What do you think things
look like in two years? You're very good
at this. I'm not saying, obviously, this
is just [\h__\h] bullshitting and
speculating, but
what's your guess?
>> I mean
>> I'm pretty heavy into Alphabet thanks to
you.
>> You went heavy into Alphabet?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, I mean
>> And then they had a 40% pop on a four
trillion dollar company. What is going
on? I mean, I haven't even watched. Is
it up? Oh, well, I mean, look.
>> This was a while back. That's
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, I mean, a while back in AI time,
which is like dog years. So, by that, I
mean, like 5 months ago.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> 5 months is like 10 years now. So, here
is why I like Google. They own the full
stack.
>> Yeah.
>> They have their own chips.
>> Yep.
>> And so, one of the things that I did a
deep dive on was the chips that they are
building, they really confused the
industry. It's my understanding that
they made an insanely high bandwidth and
kind of memory throughput when everyone
was like,
"Hey, why are you opening up these
channels and making them so high
bandwidth for this kind of like data
flow, right?" And
I talked to a buddy and he was like,
"Yeah, everyone was confused at first
when they saw the architecture for their
their latest AI chips." And then,
they realized that
we live in a world right now where a
model drops. Like, Fable goes live
tomorrow on Wednesday, right? And the
next OpenAI model goes live, you know,
in 2 weeks or whatever, cuz they have
that rumored one.
It's like old software deployment where
it was like model trained, released,
out. Model trained, released, out.
That's the cadence we're on right now.
What Google is betting, and I know I
know they're all thinking this, but what
Google is betting with this high
throughput kind of wide memory
architecture is
the future is continuous learning.
>> Mhm.
>> And so, everyone is saying like we're 12
to 18 months out, maybe a little bit
longer, from self-improving models.
>> Yeah.
>> So, 24/7, it's not no longer about like,
"Oh, Mythos came out today. Woo, crazy."
It's not about those new models
dropping. It's about
>> Just like a child learning day by day.
>> Tomorrow, it'll be better than today,
for forever.
>> Mhm.
>> And when that happens,
and they own the full stack, so Google's
got the chips. Granted, they're going to
be constrained by TSMC, which is the the
only player that's producing I mean,
there's a few others, Samsung and Micron
and a few others, but like TSMC is like
the leader. And they're producing I
believe they're producing Google's chips
as well. But they've got the chips
architecture,
they've got the models, they've got the
engineers. They're freaking I mean, they
lost a great one like a week ago, but
it's crazy what they're paying these
engineers. Did you see some of this?
It's like a billion dollars like
situation. Like it's insane what they're
paying some of these people to like
stick around.
>> Meta was doing the poach also.
>> Meta, I just don't think they're going
to make it, man.
>> Yeah.
>> Listen, they have great businesses.
Instagram is phenomenal. They've got
these fantastic assets,
but I just don't think they have
the talent to pull off what these other
bigs are pulling off, you know?
>> What do the big three look like in two
years, do you think?
Cuz like Google has a lot of ventures,
like you like you mentioned. Yeah, I
mean, also like a vast data center
expertise.
>> They have the data centers, they have
Android, yeah, which is like 60 some
percent of the population or something
like that. So, they have the install
base.
>> Mhm.
>> I have a hard time believing that if you
believe that AI inference and all the
costs associated with AI eventually kind
of settles,
and it's affordable, and yes, it'll
probably be like a Netflix type plan
where we're all like, oh yeah, that's
our extra $30 a month to get all the AI
[\h__\h] whatever. If it's coming on your
device, and also Google's powering a lot
of Apple [\h__\h] Although Apple has some
unique tech. It's interesting. Apple is
kind of coming up. I wouldn't write off
Apple either. Apple's another one, but
they're probably another couple years
out. I don't know. I mean, at the end of
the day, for me, I'm old enough now to
want not want to be like, hey, this is
the 10Xer.
>> Yeah.
>> Actually, this is interesting. I called
on your podcast. I don't know if you
know this, but like
4 years ago, I was like, dude, Nvidia's
going crush it." Blah, blah, blah.
There's some been some dumb predictions.
We've definitely made some bad ones,
too. So, I'm not going to say it's been
all good, but we've called out some
stuff.
>> In the world of AI, I don't think it's
winner take all.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> Unless somebody hits some kind of crazy
escape velocity that is like truly
it's like aware.
>> What do you think? Just I'm curious cuz
you're you're so much better at this
kind of stuff than I am. I'm like good
at my dumb little corners here and
there, but
you've worked at Google.
>> Yeah.
>> And you worked on their ill-fitted
social
product at one point, right? What was it
called?
>> Can't remember.
>> Google Plus.
>> Google Plus, right?
>> it was horrible. I left right away.
>> Right. And very wisely segued to Google
Ventures. I guess my point is like when
people think consumer, not enterprise.
When they think AI right now, they think
ChatGPT, right?
>> Yeah.
>> ChatGPT has raised a ton of [\h__\h]
money.
>> Yeah.
>> They've got to figure out ads, almost
certainly. That's not easy. That is
very, very, very hard to do. Like I'm
pretty familiar with the ads business at
Google. Very hard to do at high level,
right?
However, when
average Joe or Jane on the street thinks
AI, they think ChatGPT.
>> Mhm.
>> And when I have tried to set up the
Gmail API for Claude, the process on the
Google side is such dog [\h__\h] Like the
UX is terrible. Like it is so bad.
>> Yeah.
>> And I'd [snorts] like to think myself
reasonably decent with tech stuff, not
as not as technical as you are. But
pretty good, I would like to think.
Nonetheless, I need someone like on my
staff to walk me through step by step to
do it cuz it's so counterintuitive and
there are errors all over the place.
And then you've got, you know,
Anthropic, which is
if we are to believe the headlines, on
ARR just like crushing, right? On the
enterprise side. Like the fastest
scaling business of all time and on a
lot of different measures. However,
right? They've gotten a number of pretty
strong [\h__\h] slaps from the
administration.
At the same time, it seems
unlikely that any of these frontier labs
are going to be left unconstrained by
the government.
>> Right.
>> So, that's like a huge question mark.
>> Uh I think China will push that.
>> Okay, tell me.
>> Well, so China's been launching new
models and they just did one in like a a
week ago that is on par with Fable.
>> Was that Alibaba or someone else?
>> No, it's a
>> Doesn't matter.
>> Yeah, so it But these are open-source
models. So, it's actually really
interesting because China is like,
"Okay, listen, we're going to open
source this
and people will use our tech." They're
almost doing it the American way.
>> Yeah.
>> Like they're not close sourcing
anything. They're like, "Okay, here's
the free model. Come use ours because
you can run it yourself if you want
locally.
And that is going to be increasingly
I think that will be increasingly
common.
>> Yeah.
>> Like AMD came out, I don't know if you
saw what she of the CEO, she's
brilliant. She came out with this new
box that is this like little $4,000 box
or somewhere around there and it can run
like these massive multi-billion
parameter models locally. And so, those
charges that you were getting
for, you know, like $1,000 a month or
$5,000 a month or whatever in AI
expenses is now just that one box that
just runs the model locally. Now,
granted, it's probably 8 months behind
in terms of like the model it can run
versus the frontier models.
>> who cares?
>> For a lot of people, who cares?
>> From a business perspective.
>> Yeah.
>> And I know that's tightly related to all
sorts of technical considerations, but
where do you think Google, I still hate
hate saying Alphabet. Let's just say
Google
>> The word on the street is that they have
models that are are
more advanced than Fable. They have not
launched them because one, the
government's going to step in and stop
them.
>> Yeah.
>> And two, they're are expensive to run.
>> And
it would cost them a lot of money. They
would lose money doing so. And so, I
think in a year, we're really like 12
months we'll really know where Google's
at.
>> Mhm.
>> Cuz yeah, I'm telling you they're
holding [\h__\h] back.
>> they are.
>> They're holding [\h__\h] back cuz they have
the bankroll to do that.
>> And it's [\h__\h] Google.
>> Yeah.
>> Like you don't understand. My time
there, Sergey took me and I'm not saying
this is a flex. I'm just like this is
just what happened. Sergey took me and
Bill Maris, who ran Google Ventures,
smart dude. Bill's amazing. Through
Google X. And this was years ago. And we
got to tour and he was like, "That's the
moonshot factory." And it's like, "Dude,
you already work there and like they
make you sign [\h__\h] when you walk in."
Don't [\h__\h] say anything about Google
>> X is like the Willy Wonka.
>> So, I'm like seeing the Waymos before
they even talked about them freaking 10
plus years ago, you know, like before it
was even a thing. And so, I saw all the
crazy balloon projects and a couple
others they shuttered that I can't even
talk about, but I'm telling you
>> They're sitting on tech that's like 5
years out.
>> Yeah.
>> That like don't underestimate how many
freaking PhDs they have working on this
[\h__\h]
>> Yeah.
>> You just can't imagine what's under the
hood there.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah.
>> So, for me, I'm not a fan of like at
this point when I think about investing
into the future and this is not
investment advice, when the Anthropic's
and the OpenAIs and the Google's, like
you name the top five,
it's kind of almost like what they said
back in the day when they had the
acronym they used for like Netflix,
Google, what was the uh
>> It changes all the time.
>> But you know what I'm talking about.
>> FANG.
>> FANG, yeah. Like FANG was a thing and
then there's another one and there's
another one.
You're going to want to own like those
five, you know? And you'll sit back and
you'll be like, "Damn, if I only just
owned Google, I'd be up like 70%." But
you're like, "Oh, you know what? In
combination, I'm up like 30% and the
market's doing 10." You'll be stoked,
right?
>> sent me a graph. We can delete this if
we need to.
>> 100.
>> Yes. Yeah. So, I mean, for you looking
forward, right? Cuz you bust my balls
about some of the swings that I take,
which is is good. You should you should
No, no, you should bust my balls. I bust
it because I'm like, "Tim, what are you
optimizing for, dude? Another zero? You
don't even know the zero on the bank
account." I get it. I get it. I get it.
But I'm asking you, right? I mean, look,
we're all looking for the feeling of
being alive. Part of the way I feel
alive is by taking some swings, right?
>> Fair.
>> Okay. My question for you is,
you're not you're not just going to do
S&P 500. You got to have that high to
believe. I dabble.
Okay. So, if you were
>> you. I bought Waymo stock, and you got
pissed at me cuz I didn't offer you any.
>> He's such a prick.
>> [laughter]
>> Keeps all the the shiny stuff for
himself. He's so such a greedy little
piglet.
>> know you wanted it. Oh,
>> You 100% know that I wanted it because
[laughter]
I sent This is actually turned out
pretty well. It's part of the reason why
I pulled the trigger on Google was such
a simple approach. I took five names.
Was it It was like Google, Anthropic,
Open AI, Waymo,
handful of other companies.
And
there's Vercel, Cruise, a couple of
others. Yeah, man. And and I sent this
list out, and I sent it to like, I don't
know, five smart people I know who are
very very good investors have good track
records cross asset classes.
>> Mhm.
>> And a few of them sent that to like
their technical analysts who specialize
in different fields. And I was like,
"You
But I was like, uh maybe maybe not." And
I was like, "You have 10 chips.
Where do you put those 10 chips as a
bet? That's it." No further guidance, no
caveats, no explanation.
And look, I'm not [clears throat] saying
this is the most sophisticated
investment thesis in the world, but you
know that I wanted Waymo cuz it was on
that list, and it was one of the winners
that came back in terms of if we are to
believe the consensus of this small
cohort.
>> fair, I offered you some of my own
purchase, and you you turned me down.
>> I might still take you up on it.
>> Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Just you wait another 6 months and the
valuation will decline. I'll say, "Hey,
remember me, brother? I have I'll give
that a call.
>> Saw the news. I would love to revisit
our conversation from earlier.
>> But I think for the average person
listening like the good news is that
these companies are going out soon.
>> Yeah.
>> Like meaning they're going to be
publicly traded companies. They may seem
very expensive and very pricey and you'd
be right to say that. And so did Amazon
when it went out in 2000, you know?
>> I mean, what was the market cap when
Amazon IPO'd?
>> It was like
>> It's got to be tiny.
>> No, no, no. It's not about market cap,
it's about the price to earnings, right?
>> Yeah, okay. All right.
>> So I looked at
>> Well, now price to earnings will depend
a lot I mean, it's going to be very
different for Open AI and Anthropic,
right?
>> Well, what's crazy is SpaceX is like 30%
bump bump price earnings on the peak of
Amazon. So like SpaceX is like, did you
invest in SpaceX or no?
>> Yeah, I started investing in SpaceX like
10, 12 years ago.
>> Oh, so you're stoked.
>> Uh I mean, look, yeah, I'm fine. But you
know, I would say here also it's like if
you're like, "Oh, I missed it because
only the fancy people get to invest
beforehand." It's like, "No, I mean, uh
SpaceX right now I'm looking at the
chart
launched at 160
like had this huge bump obviously, but
then dropped down and like you could
have bought it for 156, 154, 153 and now
it's climbing back up. I mean, there's a
lot going on here and
>> Yeah.
>> honestly, I still find public equity
investing terrifying cuz there's so many
sharks and there's
>> Yeah.
>> short sellers and like derivatives and
all this craziness going on. And like
what happens when it's listed and put
into these indexes and blah blah blah
like all those dynamics are way beyond
my
>> That's why I don't do the day trading
thing.
>> I don't do day trading.
>> No, I'm just saying like for example,
SpaceX I don't have a position in
SpaceX, but if I did, it would be to
hold it for the next 10 years.
>> Here's a good takeaway. You're asking
like what's what's the takeaway from
like my
20-year analysis of the angel investing.
It's still incomplete. Like there's a
lot left to do and
>> Shopify.
>> Oh God. Well, that's a good example,
right? It's like this is going to sound
so dumb and yet duh to so many people
who are more
just better investors than I am, but
yeah, I've done pretty well. I think the
decisions I made at the time to sell
certain things were very logical given
the information and my financial status
at the time. Totally reasonable, right?
So, I don't want to judge a good poker
play based on like where I am 20 years
hence. So, that's not reasonable.
But, the takeaway is like you got to let
your winners run as long as possible.
>> 100%. I've lost more money by selling
stocks early than I've ever probably
made buying the original stock.
>> And the other thing I would say also for
people listening who are like, "Oh my
god, if these 1%ers are jerking each
other off any longer, I'm going to
vomit." If you adjust and some some very
famous firm did this, maybe it was
Sequoia or Benchmark, I can't recall,
but
they looked at
their gains from
initial investment all the way through
follow-on rounds to IPO
and then 6 months post, so after lockup
for let's just keep it simple for all
intents and purposes,
and then they looked at what you would
have gained if you bought at IPO and
just held for like 10 years, and you
would have made as much or more if you
would just bought as a retail investor.
>> Yep. There is a silver lining here,
which is I for some reason get fed a lot
of these Instagram videos.
>> You're on Instagram so much. You send me
so many [\h__\h] Instagram videos.
You do. [laughter]
>> But, the interesting thing about it is
so many times as individuals, and I've
fallen into this trap as well, which is
you find something that you love and you
buy said object when you should actually
buy the company.
>> Yeah.
>> So, so let's just pretend you're going
to spend $500 on an iPhone every year
since it came out, right?
>> Yeah.
>> And there was this great woman that came
in and she was like, "Okay, had you just
for the first 4 years of the iPhone
coming out, rather than buying an
iPhone,
>> put it in Apple.
>> put it in the Apple.
>> That's so cool.
>> And it
>> like of thousands of dollars.
>> Yeah.
>> And then my buddy is heavy like I love
you Prager. David Prager, the second the
Tesla came out, not the first one, but
the one that was consumer friendly, you
know.
>> He went and he's like he had made a
little money and he's like, you know
what? I'm going to do it. I'm going to
splurge.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm going to deck it out. I'm going to
spend a hundred grand on this thing and
he got the freaking top of the line
Tesla.
We did the math for him because we're
bastards. And it it was like fifteen
million dollars or something like that.
Had he just invested in Tesla the second
he loved the product. But the moral of
the story is if you love something and
this is going to happen over and over
again for decades to come. If you're
like, hey Claude is my [\h__\h] I use it
every single day. I think it's great
because of X, Y, and Z and they go
public like set it and forget it.
>> Yeah.
>> Come in whatever you can afford. I don't
care if it's a hundred dollars or a
thousand dollars or a hundred thousand
dollars.
It's meaningful at the end of the day.
>> I don't know. That's a
>> No, it's my right.
>> It's great advice. I mean look.
That's part of the reason that I've
gotten so much [\h__\h] from this by some
VCs. I won't mention their names who are
just like, what? Because they've got
their like thirty slide our proprietary
investment thesis [\h__\h] that they show
pension funds and stuff, right? And I'm
like
I just try to invest in stuff that I
will use every day.
>> Yeah.
>> Right? And it's not true for everything
like Commonwealth Fusion Systems. All
right, I'm not using them every day, but
SpaceX, you know, I mean outside of
Starlink, but it's like there are
exceptions, but it's like
>> Yeah.
>> with something like this, right? Where
it's like I am
eating close to half of my
>> Yeah.
>> protein calories every day of this stuff
and I'm like, I should just invest in
the company, right? It's just like
that is what makes sense. You know the
first stock I ever bought? This is when
I was like
Diltonics.
>> [laughter]
>> That'd be something you use every day.
>> Diltonics, yeah. Can't go wrong. For
people who don't know what Diltonics is
that'll be another round of show notes.
Um but the uh
it was Pixar.
>> Oh, [\h__\h]
>> Yeah, my dad bought me some book on
stock investing. Honestly, I couldn't
make any sense of it cuz it was getting
into like price to earning and this and
that, earning per share, and I was like,
"Ah, I don't really understand this."
>> That's so cool your dad bought you that
book.
>> It was cool. It was
>> Do you like
That's cool.
>> It's cool. It's cool. It was his his way
of like showing love, you know? Like, we
can't all do it in the way necessarily
people want to receive it, but
>> Yeah.
>> In any case, the point of that was I
loved comics. I tracked comics and
animation. And I saw Toy Story number
one. I even saw shorts, and I was like,
"That is the future."
>> That's amazing.
>> that's the future."
>> Exactly.
>> And when I was whatever, 15 or
something, first stock, Pixar. I have
the I have the original like shareholder
poster they mailed out
>> Oh, [\h__\h]
>> like Lasseter and Jobs and stuff.
>> Oh, dude, that's amazing.
>> Yeah. And for me, it's like, look at
your credit card statement.
Do you know what I mean? I mean, this is
not investment advice. I'm just saying
this is the way I personally approach
it, so informational
purposes only. But, it's like, yeah, if
you're spending hundreds of dollars on
like
Amazon and Amazon Prime, it's like,
well,
>> maybe,
who knows?
>> Totally.
>> You know? Are you going to be spending
more or less on that in 5 years? Like,
just forget about the market, forget
about analysts, like you personally.
Will you be spending more or less on
this in 3 or 5 years time?
>> That's exactly right.
>> Okay. And we'll put to be something in
the intro on this is not investment
advice, but it's like, to be a quant
hedge fund manager.
>> Well, and to be fair, like when you look
at Buffett's portfolio and the things
that he's bought over the years, like,
it's the consumer staples and the things
that were just like, he's like, yes,
more people will want and drink
Coca-Cola in the future. It's a
fantastic brand. The margins are
impeccable. It's a well-run business. I
know the CEO.
>> It's not prone to disruption.
>> Yeah, exactly. In downturns, guess what?
People still drink Coke.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, it's like
>> He's also a clever bastard, though. He's
been very good with his aw shucks
grandpa branding. He's very good at
that, but that dude is a stone cold
killer. In terms of
>> Yeah.
>> Geico is cash machine and
>> Yeah, I know.
>> being like the lender of first resort
when [\h__\h] goes sideways, people call
Uncle Uncle Buffett and he's like,
"Sure.
>> He's so smart.
>> Here's my offer.
Take or leave."
But yes, very bright guy.
>> All right, what did we miss?
>> Uh
I The only thing I would say is that um
>> Tell Bill Donahue.
>> Yes, that. I relaunched If you want to
learn about the latest tech and AI news,
I relaunched Digg.
>> You were showing me some numbers. That's
crazy, man.
>> It's crazy. We went from 20,000 people a
week using it to now we have close to
500,000.
So, it's been growing quite a bit and
it's pulling across the entire zeitgeist
of the web. So, we're we're like, "We
don't want to insert another social
network." So, we pull from X, we've
pulled from a few other feeds, we've
been putting in like videos from YouTube
and TikTok and others and it's just been
a fun little hobby. It's a fun hobby and
it's like doing millions of page views a
month and I'm proud of that. It's like
it's awesome to see it working again.
So, it's good.
>> digg.com
>> digg.com, @kevinrose on Instagram and uh
yeah.
>> Sweet. What should I say? I guess
tim.blog you can find thousand plus blog
posts if you want to read about my
cadaver on the table, my book sales as a
result of AI. That is a crazy blog post.
I don't even know if you're aware of
this. Oh, yeah, my uh
all format book sales.
>> Oh, I saw that.
>> Yeah, isn't that crazy?
Well, you look at the graph and it's
like stable annuity, stable annuity,
stable annuity,
very predictable and then in 2013
because what happened in November 2022?
ChatGPT 3.5.
And you see a a slip by -5%, then you
see a slip by like I'm making up these
numbers, but they're close, -28%, then
it's like -49%.
>> But it turns out you're going to be
okay. I'll be fine. The implications are
pretty interesting and now if we
continue the pace in 2026 down like 67%.
These are
These are sort of compounding in the
wrong direction, right? I mean it's not
the quite the right terminology to use
but you get it.
>> Yeah.
>> So stuff to think about. People can
check that out if you search AI
non-fiction Tim Ferriss. That's a blog
post that's actually pretty interesting
read.
But on less dystopian view ultimately
the message isn't dystopian.
tim.blog
@timferriss on Instagram @tferriss
I'm not so active on the socials cuz
I've deleted those from my phone for a
couple of years. You're listening to the
podcast so I don't have to sell the
podcast. Oh, Five Bullet Friday.
>> Mhm.
>> My diary.
>> Can you add one?
>> Can I add one what?
>> I don't know. It's like
six bullets.
>> Well every once in a while if I'm lazy
there are I'd say that's
No, if I'm lazy and I'm like ah I don't
want to do it cuz I still I still do
this thing myself. Hold on one sec.
We're almost done. Relax. You and your
prostate.
>> I No, no, it's not the [laughter]
prostate. It's the fact that we had you
gave me tequila.
>> Oh, I gave you tequila. You were
overserved. Hold on a sec. Just give me
two [\h__\h] seconds, you old man. You
old bastard.
Now I'm going to make this really long.
>> No, Tim, come [laughter] on.
>> So yeah, Five Bullet Friday every once
in a while you did this to yourself
turns into Six Bullet Saturday if I'm
just not feeling it. But yeah, 2 million
subscribers it's free, easy to
unsubscribe. tim.blog/friday
and that's all I got.
>> All right.
>> You want to go pee, old man?
>> Yeah, I will.
>> All right. Good to see you, brother.
Good to see you. Love [laughter] you,
brother.
>> Love you, too.